<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1250"?>		
		
<!--		
	Weapons	
-->		
		
<string_table>		
		
	<string id="st_trg_sako">	
		<text>Sako TRG-42</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_dynamo_hand_name">	
		<text>Rêczna £adowarka</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_dynamo_hand_descr">	
		<text>\n%c[ui_gray_1]To urz¹dzenie to cha³upniczo wykonany, rêczny generator energii elektrycznej. Zosta³ zbudowany na bazie jednofazowego asynchronicznego silniczka, pozyskanego z jakiegoœ starego przyrz¹du elektrycznego. Napiêcie przep³ywa przez transformer obni¿aj¹cy do prostownika z³o¿onego z sowieckich diod D242. Samowzbudzenie generatora odbywa siê poprzez kondensator po³¹czony z uzwojeniem pomocniczym silniczka. £adowanie odbywa poprzez rêczne obracanie wirnika, który w ruch wprawia przek³adnia œlimakowa z prêdkoœci¹ 1300-1500 obrotów/min. Urz¹dzenie zosta³o wyposa¿one w amerykañskiej produkcji amperomierz, firmy WESTON ELECTRICAL INSTRUMENT. Urz¹dzenie to jest niezwykle doceniane w Zonie, pomimo wysokiej wagi. Niektórzy rzemieœlnicy s¹ w stanie ulepszyæ to urz¹dzenie.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]CHARACTERISTICS:\n%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] motor with rated power 40 W%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] the lifetime of the motor and gearbox bearings is limited\n%c[d_cyan]</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher">	
		<text>Granatnik GP-25 "Kastior"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_descr">	
		<text>Podlufowy granatnik kalibru 40mm sowieckiej produkcji. Gwintowany, ³adowany frontowo pojedynczym granatem. Kompatybilny z karabinami szturmowymi krajów cz³onkowskich Uk³adu Warszawskiego. Zaprojektowany w celu zwiêkszenia potencjalnej si³y ra¿enia podstawowego oddzia³u piechoty. Posiada samonapinaj¹cy mechanizm spustowy z manualn¹ zapadk¹ zabezpieczaj¹c¹ i automatycznym zabezpieczeniem zapobiegaj¹cym wystrza³owi, gdy granatnik nie jest poprawnie zamontowany.\n \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] prêdkoœæ wylotowa: %c[ui_gray_1]~76 m / sek\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zasiêg ognia: %c[ui_gray_1]~300 m\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] czas prze³adowania: %c[ui_gray_1]wolny\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] amunicja: %c[ui_gray_1]Granat VOG-25 40mm</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203">	
		<text>Granatnik M203</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203_descr">	
		<text>Modyfikacja granatnika M203, w wyniku której d³ugoœæ lufy zosta³a skrócona o 3 cale, o mocowaniu przystosowanym do szyny typu Picatinny. Dziêki zmienionemu mocowaniu granatnik ten mo¿e byæ zamontowany na wiêkszoœci obecnie produkowanych karabinów z ca³ego œwiata. Pomimo nowoczeœniejszej budowy posiada niemal takie same w³aœciwoœci, jak jego sowiecki odpowiednik - GP-25.\n \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] prêdkoœæ wylotowa: %c[ui_gray_1]~76 m / sek\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zasiêg ognia: %c[ui_gray_1]~300 m\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] czas prze³adowania: %c[ui_gray_1]wolny\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] amunicja: %c[ui_gray_1]Granat 40x46 mm SR</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_9a91">	
		<text>9A-91</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_9a91_descr">	
		<text>9A91 to rosyjski subkarabinek automatyczny produkcji KBP Tu³a, zasilany nabojem 9 x 39 mm. Jego konstrukcja charakteryzuje siê d³ugim skokiem t³oka gazowego, umiejscowionego nad luf¹ oraz obrotowego zamka z 4 ryglami. Komora zamkowa zosta³a wykonana z t³oczonej stali, a czó³enko oraz uchwyt pistoletowy z polimerów. Posiada stalow¹ kolbê, sk³adan¹ w górê, do pozycji nad komor¹ zamkow¹. Regulowan¹ szczerbinkê mo¿na ustawiæ na zasiêg 100 i 200 metrów, lecz stosunkowo krótka podstawa celownika oraz stroma trajektoria poddŸwiêkowego naboju ogranicza 9A91 do zasiêgu mierz¹cego jedynie oko³o 100 metrów.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO,  PSO-1M2-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik 9A-91/VSK-94\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan">	
		<text>AN-94</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan_camo">	
		<text>AN-94 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan_descr">	
		<text>AN-94 (Automat Nikonowa) to rosyjski karabin szturmowy produkowany w latach 1993-2006, przez zak³ady I¿masz (obecnie Koncern Ka³asznikow). Jego kluczow¹ przewag¹ nad AK-74 jest wprowadzenie dodatkowego trybu 2-strza³owej serii. G³ównymi za³o¿eniami tej konstrukcji by³o opóŸnienie odrzutu, do momentu opuszczenia lufy przez pociski oraz zrównowa¿enie ruchu zamka i suwad³a, za pomoc¹ ruchomej przeciwmasy. U¿ywany przez operatorów Specnazu oraz bojowników Powinnoœci ze wzglêdu na swoje w³aœciwoœci balistyczne na stosukowo wysokich dystansach.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan_worn">	
		<text>AN-94 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ace21">	
		<text>Galil ACE-21</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ace21_descr">	
		<text>Karabin szturmowy Galil ACE zosta³ zaprojektowany i wyprodukowany przez Izraelsk¹ spó³kê IMI Systems. Wzorem dla rodziny Galil ACE by³ karabin szturmowy Galil AR, który z kolei powsta³ na bazie Automatu Ka³asznikowa. Galil ACE skupia siê na ergonomii, ³atwoœci u¿ycia oraz integracji z dodatkowym osprzêtem i elastycznoœci w warunkach bojowych - rodzina Galil ACE jest kompatybilna z trzema najpopularniejszymi rodzajami amunicji na œwiecie (5.56x45 NATO, 7.62x39 M43 i NATO 7.62x51), wraz z odpowiednimi danym kalibrom konfiguracjami d³ugoœci lufy. Ten konkretny egzemplarz jest zasilany amunicj¹ Kulow¹ 5.56x45 NATO i jest wyposa¿ony w kompaktow¹ lufê. Niezwykle rzadki widok w Zonie.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n\n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_aek971">	
		<text>AEK-971</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aek971_camo">	
		<text>AEK-971 (Kamufla¿ Powinnoœci)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aek971_camo_descr">	
		<text>Rosyjski karabin szturmowy autorstwa Siergiera Kokszarowa. Konstrukcja maj¹ca na celu zmniejszenie odrzutu oraz zredukowanie rozrzutu konkurowa³a i ostatecznie przegra³a z karabinem AN-94 jako potencjalny nastêpca AK-74N. Niewielka iloœæ karabinów AEK-971 trafi³a do rosyjskiego MSW, lecz pace nad projektem nie usta³y. W 2014 roku zmodernizowane AEK-971 wdro¿ono równolegle z AK-12, jako modele maj¹ce zast¹piæ starsze konstrukcje. Ten konkretny egzemplarz posiada jasnobe¿owy kamufla¿ z czerwonymi akcentami, maj¹cymi symbolizowaæ przynale¿noœæ do frakcji Powinnoœæ. Niektóre mechanizmy zosta³y przebudowane, lub wymienione na nowsze i bardziej niezawodne. W umiejêtnym i dbale wykonanym modyfikacjom uzyskano nieco wy¿sz¹ prêdkoœæ wylotow¹.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aek971_descr">	
		<text>Rosyjski karabin szturmowy autorstwa Siergiera Kokszarowa. Konstrukcja maj¹ca na celu zmniejszenie odrzutu oraz zredukowanie rozrzutu konkurowa³a i ostatecznie przegra³a z karabinem AN-94 jako potencjalny nastêpca AK-74N. Niewielka iloœæ karabinów AEK-971 trafi³a do rosyjskiego MSW, lecz pace nad projektem nie usta³y. W 2014 roku zmodernizowane AEK-971 wdro¿ono równolegle z AK-12, jako modele maj¹ce zast¹piæ starsze konstrukcje.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aek971_worn">	
		<text>AEK-971 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_aek973">	
		<text>AEK-973</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aek973_descr">	
		<text>AEK-973 to wersja rozwojowa karabinu AEK-971 zasilana nabojem 7,62 x 39 mm.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak">	
		<text>AK-47</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak_descr">	
		<text>Michai³ Ka³asznikow zaprojektowa³ swój automat ³¹cz¹c najlepsze cechy amerykañskiego M1 oraz niemieckiego StG44. Automat Ka³asznikowa to zasilany gazowo karabin szturmowy korzystaj¹cy z naboju o kalibrze 7.62x39 mm. Jest prawdopodobnie najbardziej uznanym na œwiecie modelem broni palnej drugiej po³owy XX wieku. By³ i nadal jest - w bardziej lub mniej zmodernizowanej formie - produkowany w dziesi¹tkach krajów na ca³ym œwiecie i by³ u¿yty w setkach ró¿nych konfliktów od momentu powstania pierwowzoru.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik PBS-1\n%c[d_red]
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: %c[d_red]brak, ze wzglêdu na brak szyny monta¿owej\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak101">	
		<text>AK-101</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak101_camo">	
		<text>AK-101 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak101_descr">	
		<text>AK-101 to karabin szturmowy oparty na konstrukcji AK-74M, przeznaczony na rynek eksportowy. Jest zasilany standardowym dla wiêkszoœci krajów cz³onkowskich NATO nabojem 5.56x45mm. AK-101 jest przeznaczony dla potencjalnych nabywców szukaj¹cych broni ³¹cz¹cej logistyczne walory naboju 5.56x45mm NATO z niezawodnoœci¹ Ka³asznikowa. Zbudowano go z u¿yciem nowoczesnych polimerów i materia³ów kompozytowych w calu zredukowania wagi oraz zwiêkszenia celnoœci. Wiele ulepszeñ zawartych w tej konstrukcji jest równie¿ obecnych w AK-103 i pozosta³ych modelach serii AK-10x.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik ATG\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak102">	
		<text>AK-102</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak102_descr">	
		<text>AK-102 to skrócona wersja karabinu szturmowego AK-101. Stanowi kompromis pomiêdzy pe³nej d³ugoœci karabinem i kompaktowym AKS-74U. Komora zamkowa zosta³a wykonana z t³oczonej stali, a magazynek ze wzmocnionych w³ókien szklanych. Kolba sk³ada siê w ca³oœci z pustego w œrodku plastiku. Pozwoli³o to na zredukowanie wagi oraz trwa³oœci, zarówno jak i umo¿liwi³o przechowywanie w niej polowego zestawu naprawczego.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech, EKP-8-02 Kobra, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik ATG\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak103">	
		<text>AK-103</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak103_camo">	
		<text>AK-103 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak103_descr">	
		<text>AK-103 to karabin szturmowy oparty na konstrukcji AK-74M, strzelaj¹cy nabojem 7.62x39mm, co czyni go nastêpc¹ karabinu AKM. AK-103 jest kompatybilny z szeregiem celowników optycznych o ró¿nych przeznaczeniach, wraz z t³umikiem oraz granatnikiem GP-25. W celu zmniejszenia wagi w konstrukcji zastosowano polimery gdziekolwiek by³o to mo¿liwe, pozbywaj¹c siê ciê¿szego drewna i metalu.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik ATG\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak104">	
		<text>AK-104</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak104_descr">	
		<text>AK-104 to skrócona wersja karabinu szturmowego AK-103. Stanowi kompromis pomiêdzy pe³nej d³ugoœci karabinem i kompaktowym AKS-74U. Komorê zamkow¹ wykonano z t³oczonej stali, a magazynek ze wzmocnionych w³ókien szklanych. Kolba sk³ada siê w ca³oœci z pustego w œrodku plastiku. Pozwoli³o to na zredukowanie wagi oraz trwa³oœci, zarówno jak i umo¿liwi³o przechowywanie w niej polowego zestawu naprawczego.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik ATG\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak105">	
		<text>AK-105</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak105_descr">	
		<text>AK-105 to skrócona wersja karabinu AK-74M uzupe³niaj¹ca karabinki AKS-74U w s³u¿bie Rosyjskiej Armii. Konstrukcja zosta³a przystosowana do walki w przestrzeniach zamkniêtych kosztem zmniejszonej skutecznoœci na d³ugim dystansie. Komorê zamkow¹ wykonano z t³oczonej stali, a magazynek ze wzmocnionych w³ókien szklanych. Kolba sk³ada siê w ca³oœci z pustego w œrodku plastiku. Pozwoli³o to na zredukowanie wagi oraz trwa³oœci, zarówno jak i umo¿liwi³o przechowywanie w niej polowego zestawu naprawczego.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP 1S-03 "Kobra", 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak12">	
		<text>AK-12</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak12_descr">	
		<text>Karabin szturmowy AK-12 jest najnowsz¹ konstrukcj¹ fabryki I¿masz. Ma ona zast¹piæ starsze modele serii 74M i 10x zarówno w u¿ytku krajowym, jak i eksportowym. Jest to zasilany gazowo karabin z selektywny trybem ognia u¿ywaj¹cy tradycyjnego, typowego dla Ka³asznikowa spustu z t³okiem gazowym o d³ugim skoku oraz obrotowym ryglem. Masa komory zamkowej zosta³a zauwa¿alnie zmniejszona w celu zredukowania odrzutu i zwiêkszenia celnoœci ognia ci¹g³ego.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74">	
		<text>AK-74N</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_alt">	
		<text>AK-74N (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_custom">	
		<text>AK-74N (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_descr">	
		<text>AK-74 to karabin szturmowy kalibru 5.45x45mm rozwijany na pocz¹tku lat '70 przez Michai³a Ka³asznikowa w celu zast¹pienia karabinu AKM. Wprowadzony w roku 1974, zadebiutowa³ podczas radzieckiej interwencji w konflikcie w Afganistanie. W odró¿nieniu od karabinu AKM, AK-74N dostosowano do strzelania mniejszym nabojem kalibru 5.45x45mm oraz wyposa¿ono w wiêkszy hamulec wylotowy.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_eot">	
		<text>AK-74N "EOTech"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_eot_descr">	
		<text>AK-74 to karabin szturmowy kalibru 5.45x45mm rozwijany na pocz¹tku lat '70 przez Michai³a Ka³asznikowa w celu zast¹pienia karabinu AKM. Wprowadzony w roku 1974, zadebiutowa³ podczas radzieckiej interwencji w konflikcie w Afganistanie. W odró¿nieniu od karabinu AKM, AK-74N dostosowano do strzelania mniejszym nabojem kalibru 5.45x45mm oraz wyposa¿ono w wiêkszy hamulec wylotowy. Ten konkretny egzemplarz posiada zintegrowany celownik holograficzny EOTech oraz powiêkszony, 45-nabojowy magazynek.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany celownik EOTech\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_modern">	
		<text>AK-74N (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_old">	
		<text>AK-74</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_old_descr">	
		<text>AK-74 to karabin szturmowy kalibru 5.45x45mm rozwijany na pocz¹tku lat '70 przez Michai³a Ka³asznikowa w celu zast¹pienia karabinu AKM. Wprowadzony w roku 1974, zadebiutowa³ podczas radzieckiej interwencji w konflikcie w Afganistanie. W odró¿nieniu od karabinu AKM, AK-74N dostosowano do strzelania mniejszym nabojem kalibru 5.45x45mm oraz wyposa¿ono w wiêkszy hamulec wylotowy. Oznakowania i numer seryjny wskazuj¹, ¿e jest to wczesny model z pocz¹tku produkcji.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: %c[d_red]brak, ze wzglêdu na brak szyny monta¿owej\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_rusty"> <!-- unused -->	
		<text>AK-74N (rusty)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_rusty_descr">	
		<text>The AK-74 is a 5.45x45mm assault rifle developed in the early 1970s by Mikhail Kalashnikov to replace the earlier AKM. It was introduced in 1974 and first saw service with Soviet forces engaged in the Afghanistan Conflict. The AKM rifle was adapted to fire smaller 5.45x45mm cartridge and fitted with a large muzzle brake. This model seems to be very rusty and unreliable.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_worn">	
		<text>AK-74N (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m">	
		<text>AK-74M</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_alt">	
		<text>AK-74M (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_camo">	
		<text>AK-74M (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_custom">	
		<text>AK-74M (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_descr">	
		<text>W roku 1991 fabryka I¿masz rozpoczê³a produkcjê zmodernizowanego AK-74 o oznaczeniu M. Poza kilkoma pomniejszymi usprawnieniami, karabin wyposa¿ono w now¹, sk³adan¹ kolbê wykonan¹ z poliamidu. AK-74M posiada równie¿ wzmocniony hamulec wylotowy i pokrywê komory zamkowej. Ka¿dy AK-74M wyposa¿ono boczn¹ szynê monta¿ow¹ do montowania pomocniczej optyki. Od roku 1991 AK-74M zosta³ wprowadzony do czynnej s³u¿by w armii rosyjskiej, jako broñ zasadnicza.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_duty">	
		<text>AK-74M (Kamufla¿ Powinnoœci)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_pk-a">	
		<text>AK-74M PK-A</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_pk-a_descr">	
		<text>W roku 1991 fabryka I¿masz rozpoczê³a produkcjê zmodernizowanego AK-74 o oznaczeniu M. Poza kilkoma pomniejszymi usprawnieniami, karabin wyposa¿ono w now¹, sk³adan¹ kolbê wykonan¹ z poliamidu. AK-74M posiada równie¿ wzmocniony hamulec wylotowy i pokrywê komory zamkowej. Ka¿dy AK-74M wyposa¿ono boczn¹ szynê monta¿ow¹ do montowania pomocniczej optyki. Od roku 1991 AK-74M zosta³ wprowadzony do czynnej s³u¿by w armii rosyjskiej, jako broñ zasadnicza. Ten egzemplarz wyposa¿ono w celownik PK-A zainstalowany na mocowaniu MTK-83.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany celownik PK-A\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_worn">	
		<text>AK-74M (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u">	
		<text>AKS-74UN</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_camo">	
		<text>AKS-74UN (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_custom">	
		<text>AKS-74UN (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_descr">	
		<text>AKS-74U to subkarabinek automatyczny oryginalnie przeznaczony dla oddzia³ów Specnazu, spadochroniarzy, stra¿y tylnej i obs³ugi pojazdów pancernych; grup, które potrzebuj¹ kompaktowej broni automatycznej o sile ra¿enia wiêkszej, ni¿ pistolet. Litera S w oznaczeniu AKS-74U oznacza "Sk³adnoj", czyli sk³adan¹, metalow¹ kolby. Z kolei litera U oznacza "Ukrócenyj", w odniesieniu do skróconej lufy. Obie te modyfikacje czyni¹ AKS-74U du¿o bardziej mobilnym i porêcznym w ciasnych przestrzeniach w porónaniu do AKS-74. Wzamian za mobilnoœæ, karabinek przyp³aci³ znacznie ograniczon¹ prêdkoœci¹ wylotow¹, a co za tym idzie - zredukowanym zasiêgiem ostrza³u.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik PBS-4\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_old">	
		<text>AKS-74U</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_old_descr">	
		<text>AKS-74U to subkarabinek automatyczny oryginalnie przeznaczony dla oddzia³ów Specnazu, spadochroniarzy, stra¿y tylnej i obs³ugi pojazdów pancernych; grup, które potrzebuj¹ kompaktowej broni automatycznej o sile ra¿enia wiêkszej, ni¿ pistolet. Litera S w oznaczeniu AKS-74U oznacza "Sk³adnoj", czyli sk³adan¹, metalow¹ kolby. Z kolei litera U oznacza "Ukrócenyj", w odniesieniu do skróconej lufy. Obie te modyfikacje czyni¹ AKS-74U du¿o bardziej mobilnym i porêcznym w ciasnych przestrzeniach w porónaniu do AKS-74. Wzamian za mobilnoœæ, karabinek przyp³aci³ znacznie ograniczon¹ prêdkoœci¹ wylotow¹, a co za tym idzie - zredukowanym zasiêgiem ostrza³u. Oznakowania i numer seryjny wskazuj¹, ¿e jest to wczesny model z pocz¹tku produkcji.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] Brak, ze wzglêdu na brak szyny monta¿owej\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik PBS-4\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_rusty">	
		<text>AKS-74UN (zardzewia³y)</text> <!-- unused -->
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_rusty_descr">	
		<text>The AKS-74U was intended for use mainly by Spetsnaz units, airborne infantry, rear-echelon support units and armoured vehicle crews, who require a compact but relatively powerful individual automatic weapon. The AKS-74U is significantly more manoeuvrable in tight quarters than the AKS-74, but a significant decline in prêdkoœæ wylotowa resulted in a decrease in effective range. This model has visible rust on it.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag">	
		<text>AKS-74UNB (zmodyfikowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag_descr">	
		<text>AKS-74U to subkarabinek automatyczny oryginalnie przeznaczony dla oddzia³ów Specnazu, spadochroniarzy, stra¿y tylnej i obs³ugi pojazdów pancernych; grup, które potrzebuj¹ kompaktowej broni automatycznej o sile ra¿enia wiêkszej, ni¿ pistolet. Litera S w oznaczeniu AKS-74U oznacza "Sk³adnoj", czyli sk³adan¹, metalow¹ kolby. Z kolei litera U oznacza "Ukrócenyj", w odniesieniu do skróconej lufy. Obie te modyfikacje czyni¹ AKS-74U du¿o bardziej mobilnym i porêcznym w ciasnych przestrzeniach w porónaniu do AKS-74. Wzamian za mobilnoœæ, karabinek przyp³aci³ znacznie ograniczon¹ prêdkoœci¹ wylotow¹, a co za tym idzie - zredukowanym zasiêgiem ostrza³u. Ten konkretny egzemplarz posiada 45-nabojowy magazynek z karabinu RPK, zintegrowany celownik Kobra oraz zintegrowany t³umik.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany celownik EKP-1S-03 Kobra\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany t³umik PBS-4\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_worn">	
		<text>AKS-74UN (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_akm">	
		<text>AKMN</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_akm_descr">	
		<text>AKM to karabin szturmowy kalibru 7.62x39mm. Jest to wersja rozwojowa karabinu AK-47 (litera M oznacza "Modernizowanyj") zaprojektowana przez Michai³a Ka³asznikowa w latach '50. Modernizacja polega³a na uproszczeniu konstrukcji i lepszym rozk³adzie masy. Wprowadzony do s³u¿by w Armii Czerwonej w roku 1959, AKM jest najbardziej powszechnym wariantem serii karabinów AK. Znalaz³ zastosowanie wœród krajów cz³onkowskich Traktatu Warszawskiego oraz sojuszniczych krajów na terenie Afryki i Azji. Produkcja karabinów AKM zosta³a rozpoczêta przez Fabrykê Broni Tu³a i I¿ewskie Zak³ady Mechaniczne.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik PBS-1\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_akm_worn">	
		<text>AKMN (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_akms">	
		<text>AKMSN</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_akms_alt">	
		<text>AKMSN (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_akms_descr">	
		<text>Wariant karabinu AKM wyposa¿ony w sk³adan¹ do do³u, metalow¹ kolbê. Ró¿ni siê ona od kolby karabinu AK-47 zmodyfikowanym mechanizmem blokuj¹cym, która blokuje oba, zamiast tylko jednego z ramion.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik PBS-1\n
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_akms_worn">	
		<text>AKMSN (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_aks">	
		<text>AKS-47</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aks_descr">	
		<text>Wariant karabinu AK-47 wyposa¿ony w sk³adan¹ do do³u, metalow¹ kolbê. Zaprojektowany do u¿ytku przez za³ogi pojazdów opancerzonych i spadochroniarzy.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
		%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] optyka: brak, ze wzglêdu na brak szyny monta¿owej\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik PBS-1\n
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aks74">	
		<text>AKS-74N</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aks74_descr">	
		<text>Bêd¹c celniejsz¹ i bardziej niezawodn¹ wersj¹ karabinu AKM, AK-74 jest u¿ywany przez kraje powsta³e po upadku ZSRR po dziœ dzieñ. Posiada trójk¹tn¹ metalow¹ kolbê, sk³adan¹ do lewej strony. W odró¿nieniu od AKMS nie posiada sk³adanego oparcia na ramiê.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aks74_new">	
		<text>AKS-74N (nowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aks74_rusty">	
		<text>AKS-74N (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aks74_rusty_descr">	
		<text>A more accurate and reliable rifle than the AKM, the AK-74 is still used by the majority of countries of the former USSR. The AKS-74 is the foldable stock version of AK-74 and its stock has a triangular shape and lacks the folding shoulder pad of the AKMS and is folded to the left side of the receiver. This model is rusty and thus not very reliable.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik GP-25 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aks74_worn">	
		<text>AKS-74N (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_aps">	
		<text>APS</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aps_descr">	
		<text>Automatyczny Pistolet Steczkina - APS to rosyjski pistolet maszynowy nosz¹cy imiê swojego konstruktora, Igora Steczkina. APS by³ oryginalnie zasilany nabojem kalibru 7.62x25mm Tokariew, po czym przekalibrowano go do 9x18mm u¿ywanego w nowym pistolecie Makarowa, po tym jak uznano, ¿e nabój ten stanie siê standardem amunicji pistoletowej w Armii Radzieckiej. W roku 1951, 'Steczkin' wraz z 'Makarowem' zosta³y wprowadzone do s³u¿by w Radzieckim arsenale, zastêpuj¹c starzej¹cy siê TT-33.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik APS\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aps_worn">	
		<text>APS (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_aug">	
		<text>Steyr AUG A1</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_custom">	
		<text>Steyr AUG A1 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_descr">	
		<text>Steyr AUG to karabin typu bullpup, zasilany nabojem kalibru 5.56mm. Zaprojektowany w latach '60 przez zak³¹dy Steyr Mannlicher GmbH &amp; Co KG (poprzednio znane jako Steyr-Daimler-Puch). AUG (Armee-Universal-Gewehr "uniwersalny karabin wojskowy") zosta³ wdro¿ony do Austriackiej Armii jako StG 77 (Sturmgewehr 77) w roku 1978, zastêpuj¹c StG 58 (FN FAL produkowany na licencji). W s³u¿bie od 1978 do chwili obecnej, jest standardow¹ broni¹ Austriackiej Bundeswehry i wielu jednostek policyjnych.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta 1.5x\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_freedom">	
		<text>Steyr AUG A1 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_merc">	
		<text>Steyr AUG A1 (zmodyfikowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_modern">	
		<text>Steyr AUG A1 (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_modern_descr">	
		<text>Steyr AUG to karabin typu bullpup, zasilany nabojem kalibru 5.56mm. Zaprojektowany w latach '60 przez zak³¹dy Steyr Mannlicher GmbH &amp; Co KG (poprzednio znane jako Steyr-Daimler-Puch). AUG (Armee-Universal-Gewehr "uniwersalny karabin wojskowy") zosta³ wdro¿ony do Austriackiej Armii jako StG 77 (Sturmgewehr 77) w roku 1978, zastêpuj¹c StG 58 (FN FAL produkowany na licencji). W s³u¿bie od 1978 do chwili obecnej, jest standardow¹ broni¹ Austriackiej Bundeswehry i wielu jednostek policyjnych.\n \n Ten konkretny egzemplarz zosta³ przekalibrowany pod nabój 7.62x51 NATO.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta 1.5x\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_worn">	
		<text>Steyr AUG A1 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta">	
		<text>Beretta 92F</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_alt">	
		<text>Beretta 92F (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_camo">	
		<text>Beretta 92F (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_descr">	
		<text>92F to w³oski pistolet samopowtarzalny, najlepiej znany jako standardowy pistolet wojsk l¹dowych Stanów Zjednoczonych, nastêpca legendarnego M1911. Obs³ugiwany krótkim odrzutem, z ryglowanym zamkiem i aluminiow¹ konstrukcj¹ z twardo chromowanym gwintem lufy. Wdro¿ony do s³u¿by w wielu krajach, oraz popularny wœród kryminalistów, ze wzglêdu na wysok¹ si³ê ra¿enia i du¿¹ pojemnoœæ magazynka.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z 9x19 (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_modern">	
		<text>Beretta 92F (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_rusty">	
		<text>Beretta 92F (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_rusty_descr">	
		<text>The 92F is perhaps best known as the standard pistol of the US Military, replacing the legendary M1911. It is a short-recoil operated, locked-breech weapon with an aluminium frame and a hard chromed barrel bore. A popular sidearm adopted by several countries, it is especially popular among criminals for its high-powered rounds and high-capacity magazine. This model became rusty over time, resulting in low reliablity.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_worn">	
		<text>Beretta 92F (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_bizon">	
		<text>PP-19 Bizon</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bizon_descr">	
		<text>Rosyjski pistolet maszynowy kalibru 9x18mm Makarow. Zaprojetkowany w I¿ewsku, w s³awnej fabryce I¿masz we wczesnych latach '90. Wdro¿ony do s³u¿by w roku 1996 na potrzeby jednostek antyterrorystycznych. Niew¹tpliwie wzorowany na amerykañskim Calico M960, konstrukcja Bizona ³¹czy wysokiej pojemnoœci magazynek œlimakowy z bardziej konwencjonalnym uk³adem czêœci. Zbudowano go bowiem na bazie skróconej komory zamkowej karabinu AKS-74, wykonanej ze stali t³oczonej. Wyposa¿ony w prosty zamek swobodny, z kurkiem detonuj¹cym ³adunek z zamkniêtego rygla. Bizon jest posiada pó³automatyczny, zarówno jak i automatyczny tryb ognia, wraz z typowym dla AK bezpiecznkiem - dŸwigni¹ po prawej stronie komory zamkowej. Celownik zbli¿ony do AKS-74U, z os³onionym przednim s³upkiem i szczerbin¹ na krzywce.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik PBS-1\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16">	
		<text>TOZ-66 (obrzyn)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_alt">	
		<text>TOZ-66 (alternatywny obrzyn)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_descr">	
		<text>Dubeltówka ze skróconymi lufami. L¿ejsza i bardziej kompaktowa, efektywna na bliskim dystansie. Potrzebuj¹c taniej, lecz efektywnej broni niskiego zasiêgu, wielu kotów decyduje siê na obciêcie kolby i lufy szeroko dostêpnej strzelby TOZ 66.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_full">	
		<text>TOZ-66</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_full_alt">	
		<text>TOZ-66 (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_full_descr">	
		<text>Potê¿na broñ, na któr¹ staæ niemal ka¿dego stalkera. TOZ-66 to ³amana dubeltówka kurkowa produkowana przez Fabrykê Broni Tula. W Zonie znana jako efektywna i niezawodna broñ krótkiego zasiêgu. Jednak ze wzglêdu na swój rozmar i nieporêcznoœæ wielu stalkerów decyduje siê na wydanie swoich ciê¿ko zarobionych rubli na zakup wspó³czesnego pistoletu.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_full_rusty">	
		<text>TOZ-66 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_full_worn">	
		<text>TOZ-66 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_rusty">	
		<text>TOZ-66 (zardzewia³y obrzyn)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_worn">	
		<text>TOZ-66 (u¿ywany obrzyn)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_colt_kimber">	
		<text>Kimber Desert Warrior</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt_kimber_descr">	
		<text>Zaawansowany wariant pistoletu Colt M1911A1 zaprojektowany przez Kimber Manufacturing. Desert Warrior zosta³ opracowany z myœl¹ o operacjach specjalnych wojsk USA.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911">	
		<text>Colt M1911</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_alt">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_camo">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_camo_descr">	
		<text>M1911 by³ standardow¹ broni¹ boczn¹ si³ zbrojnych Stanów Zjednocznonych od 1911 do 1985 roku. Ten wyj¹tkowo niezawodny i wytrzyma³y pistolet zosta³ wdro¿ony do s³u¿by w wojsku, policji oraz u¿ytku cywilnego na ca³ym œwiecie, a jego poplarnoœæ wci¹¿ nie maleje. Ten unikalny model posiada ciemnobe¿ony kamufla¿ z czerwonymi akcentami.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik .45 ACP (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_custom">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_descr">	
		<text>M1911 by³ standardow¹ broni¹ boczn¹ si³ zbrojnych Stanów Zjednocznonych od 1911 do 1985 roku. Ten wyj¹tkowo niezawodny i wytrzyma³y pistolet zosta³ wdro¿ony do s³u¿by w wojsku, policji oraz u¿ytku cywilnego na ca³ym œwiecie, a jego poplarnoœæ wci¹¿ nie maleje.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik .45 ACP (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_duty">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (Kamufla¿ Powinnoœci)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_duty_descr">	
		<text>M1911 by³ standardow¹ broni¹ boczn¹ si³ zbrojnych Stanów Zjednocznonych od 1911 do 1985 roku. Ten wyj¹tkowo niezawodny i wytrzyma³y pistolet zosta³ wdro¿ony do s³u¿by w wojsku, policji oraz u¿ytku cywilnego na ca³ym œwiecie, a jego poplarnoœæ wci¹¿ nie maleje. Ten konkretny egzemplarz zosta³ zmodyfikowany w celu zwiêkszenia prêdkoœci wylotowej pocisku.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik .45 ACP (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_merc">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (Kamufla¿ Najemników)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_merc_descr">	
		<text>M1911 by³ standardow¹ broni¹ boczn¹ si³ zbrojnych Stanów Zjednocznonych od 1911 do 1985 roku. Ten wyj¹tkowo niezawodny i wytrzyma³y pistolet zosta³ wdro¿ony do s³u¿by w wojsku, policji oraz u¿ytku cywilnego na ca³ym œwiecie, a jego poplarnoœæ wci¹¿ nie maleje. Ten konkrenty egzemplarz zosta³ zmodyfikowany w celu zwiêkszenia celnoœci.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik .45 ACP (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_modern">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_new">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (nowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_rusty">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_rusty_descr">	
		<text>The M1911 was the standard-issue side arm for the US military from 1911 to 1985. An extremely reliable and robust weapon, it's been adopted for military, police and civilian use around the world and remains a very popular firearm to this day. This model has rust all over the place, which will likely increase a probability of it jamming.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_worn">	
		<text>Colt M1911 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_cz75">	
		<text>CZ 75</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_cz75_auto">	
		<text>CZ 75 Auto</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_cz75_auto_descr">	
		<text>CZ 75 to czeski pistolet samopowtarzalny kalibru 9x19mm Parabellum, zaprojektowany przez Josefa i Františka Kouckich, produkowany przez zak³ady ÈZUB.  CZ-75 skupia najlepsze cechy poprzedzaj¹cych go konstrukcji, dziêki czemu otrzymano estetyczny, wygodny i ³atwy w obs³udze pistolet, który sta³ siê póŸniej baz¹ dla wielu innych projektów. CZ-75 Auto to model z 1995 roku, z d³u¿sz¹ luf¹ i mo¿liwoœci¹ prowadzenia ognia ci¹g³ego.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_cz75_custom">	
		<text>CZ 75 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_cz75_descr">	
		<text>CZ 75 to czeski pistolet samopowtarzalny kalibru 9x19mm Parabellum, zaprojektowany przez Josefa i Františka Kouckich, produkowany przez zak³ady ÈZUB. CZ-75 skupia najlepsze cechy poprzedzaj¹cych go konstrukcji, dziêki czemu otrzymano estetyczny, wygodny i ³atwy w obs³udze pistolet, który sta³ siê póŸniej baz¹ dla wielu innych projektów.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z 9x19</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_cz75_worn">	
		<text>CZ-75 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle">	
		<text>Desert Eagle</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_custom">	
		<text>Desert Eagle (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_descr">	
		<text>Desert Eagle to niekonwencjonalny pistolet na amunicjê rewolwerow¹ opracowany w 1979 roku przez firmê Magnum Research Inc., a nastêpnie produkowany na licencji przez izrealski koncern IMI. Pistolet ten zosta³ opracowany jako specjalistyczna broñ do polowania na œredni¹ i du¿¹ zwierzynê. Ze wzglêdu na cenê, wagê i wymiary, a tak¿e fakt, ¿e w ka¿dym z powy¿szych parametrów mo¿na pomieœciæ dwa inne pistolety, broñ ta nie jest zbyt powszechna w Zonie.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_modern">	
		<text>Desert Eagle (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_nimble">	
		<text>Desert Eagle "Steppe Eagle"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_nimble_descr">	
		<text>Desert Eagle to niekonwencjonalny pistolet na amunicjê rewolwerow¹ opracowany w 1979 roku przez firmê Magnum Research Inc., a nastêpnie produkowany na licencji przez izrealski koncern IMI. Pistolet ten zosta³ opracowany jako specjalistyczna broñ do polowania na œredni¹ i du¿¹ zwierzynê, a tak¿e do strzelania na odleg³oœæ do piêædziesiêciu metrów. Ze wzglêdu na cenê, wagê i wymiary, a tak¿e fakt, ¿e w ka¿dym z powy¿szych parametrów mo¿na pomieœciæ dwa inne pistolety, broñ ta nie jest zbyt powszechna w Zonie. Ten egzemplarz trafi³ do Zony w posiadaniu stalkera zwanego Loganem Williamsem. Pod przykrywk¹ bycia fotografem magazynu TIME zdo³a³ w pojedynkê dotrzeæ do samego centrum Prypeci. Jego miejsce pobytu jest obecnie nieznane, ale kr¹¿¹ plotki, ¿e pracuje teraz jako broker informacji specjalizuj¹cy siê we wszelkich tematach zwi¹znych z Zon¹.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany celownik DOCTER</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_worn">	
		<text>Desert Eagle (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000">	
		<text>FN F2000</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_camo">	
		<text>FN F2000 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_custom">	
		<text>FN F2000 (zmodyfikowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_descr">	
		<text>FN F2000 to modu³owy system broni strzeleckiej produkowany od 2001 roku przez belgijsk¹ fabrykê broni FN Herstall. Jego podstawowa konfiguracja to karabin szturmowy typu bullpup zasilany nabojem kalibru 5,56x45mm NATO. F2000 ofreuje wszystkie zalety znane z popularnych wspó³czesnych karabinów, takie jak kompaktowoœæ, oburêcznoœæ i szeroki wybór modu³ów i dodatków. Do tej pory FN F2000 znalaz³ tylko kilku kupców, takich jak Si³y Zbrojne S³owenii, czy Belgijskie S³u¿by Specjalne.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta FN2000\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_nimble">	
		<text>FN F2000 EOTech</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_nimble_descr">	
		<text>FN F2000 to modu³owy system broni strzeleckiej produkowany od 2001 roku przez belgijsk¹ fabrykê broni FN Herstall. Jego podstawowa konfiguracja to karabin szturmowy typu bullpup zasilany nabojem kalibru 5,56x45mm NATO. F2000 ofreuje wszystkie zalety znane z popularnych wspó³czesnych karabinów, takie jak kompaktowoœæ, oburêcznoœæ i szeroki wybór modu³ów i dodatków. Do tej pory FN F2000 znalaz³ tylko kilku kupców, takich jak Si³y Zbrojne S³owenii, czy Belgijskie S³u¿by Specjalne. Ten konkretny egzamplarz posiada zintegrowany celownik EOTech, który poprawia wygodê podczas walki w przestrzeniach zamkniêtych kosztem ogólnej celnoœci. Zwiêkszono w nim tak¿e szybkostrzelnoœæ.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany celownik EOTech\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_worn">	
		<text>FN F2000 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_fn57">	
		<text>FN Five-seveN</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fn57_descr">	
		<text>Five-seveN to pó³automatyczny pistolet z zamkiem pó³swobodnym zaprojektowany przez FN Herstal jako broñ uzupe³niaj¹ca do pistoletu maszynowego P90. P90 i Five-seveN dziel¹ ten sam rodzaj amunicji - 5.7x28mm SS190. G³ównym zamys³em tych broni oraz ich amunicji by³o umo¿liwienie du¿ej si³y penetracji pancerza zachowuj¹c przy tym nisk¹ masê, odrzut i rozmiar broni.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_fnp45">	
		<text>FNP-45</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fnp45_custom">	
		<text>FNP-45 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fnp45_descr">	
		<text>FN FNP to seria pó³automatycznych pistoletów o polimerowej ramie konstruowanych przez FNH USA - poddzia³ FN Herstal w Po³udniowej Karolinie. Zadebiutowa³y na pocz¹tku 2006 roku. Seria FNP to pistolety kurkowe z zewnêtrzym ekstraktorem. Zespó³ spustowy jest umieszczony w polimerowej ramie jako indywidualny element po³¹czony z kurkiem. Zamek wykonano ze stali nierdzewnej. Posiada oburêczn¹ dŸwigniê odbezpieczaj¹c¹ i regulowany przycisk zwolnienia magazynka. \n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik GemTech</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fnp45_worn">	
		<text>FNP-45 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_fnx45">	
		<text>FNX-45 Tactical</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fnx45_alt">	
		<text>FNX-45 Tactical (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fnx45_custom">	
		<text>FNX-45 Tactical (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fnx45_descr">	
		<text>FN FNX to seria pó³automatycznych pistoletów o polimerowej ramie konstruowanych przez FNH USA - poddzia³ FN Herstal w Po³udniowej Karolinie. Pocz¹tkowo rozwijane jedynie na potrzeby policji, obecnie s¹ produkowane na terenie Stanów Zjednocznych do u¿ytku przez wojsko, policjê i cywilów. Wszystkie pistolety FNX s¹ pó³automatyczne, z dwustopniowym/jednostopniowym spustem i zewnêntrzym kurkiem. Rama ka¿dego pistoletu FNX jest wykonana z odpornych na uderzenia polimerów, z wymiennymi nak³adkami na uchwyt o ró¿nych rozmiarach. FNX-45 to wyspecjalizowany wariant podstawowego FNX-45, posiadaj¹cy podniesione przyrz¹dy celownicze i przed³u¿on¹ lufê, gwintowan¹ do u¿ytku z t³umikiem.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany celownik FNX Tactical\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany t³umik GemTech</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_fort">	
		<text>Fort-17</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_descr">	
		<text>Fort-17 to najnowsza konstrukcja narodowej Ukraiñskiej fabryki FORT. Modyfikacja wzglêdem wczeœniejszego Forta-12 polega na zmianie metalowej ramy na polimerow¹. Konstrukcja wewnêtrzna pozosta³a niemal identyczna. Modernizacja pozwoli³a na znaczne zmniejszenie wagi oraz zaimplementowanie wymiennych nak³adek na uchwyt, pozwalaj¹cych na lepsze dostosowanie broni do strzelca.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z 9x19</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_rusty">	
		<text>Fort-17 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_rusty_descr">	
		<text>The Fort-17 pistol is the latest development of the Ukrainian state owned FORT factory. It is a polymer framed modification of the earlier Fort-12 pistol, and all the mechanisms and properties are almost identical between the two pistols. However, the Fort-17 is lighter than its predecessor and features a removable grip backstrap, which can be had in various sizes, to adapt the pistol for a particular shooter. Because of its poor physical condition, this model can jam often. \n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_snag">	
		<text>Fort-17 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_snag_descr">	
		<text>Fort-17 to najnowsza konstrukcja narodowej Ukraiñskiej fabryki FORT. Modyfikacja wzglêdem wczeœniejszego Forta-12 polega na zmianie metalowej ramy na polimerow¹. Konstrukcja wewnêtrzna pozosta³a niemal identyczna. Modernizacja pozwoli³a na znaczne zmniejszenie wagi oraz zaimplementowanie wymiennych nak³adek na uchwyt, pozwalaj¹cych na lepsze dostosowanie broni do strzelca. Ten egzemplarz nale¿a³ do Sêka.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z 9x19</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_worn">	
		<text>Fort-17 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_g3">	
		<text>G3A3</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g3_descr">	
		<text>G3A3 to niemiecki karabin automatyczny produkowany od 1959 roku przez Heckler &amp; Koch GmbH w kolaboracji z Hiszapñsk¹ agencj¹ CETME (Centro de Estudios Tecnicos de Materiales Especiales). Zasilany nabojem 7.62x51mm NATO, jest broni¹ samoczynno-samopowtarzaln¹ dzia³aj¹c¹ na zasadzie odrzutu zamka pó³swobodnego, hamowanego ³o¿yskami. Zosta³ przyjêty do s³u¿by w niemieckiej Bundeswehrze w 1959 roku i pozosta³ w niej do roku 1995, gdy jego miejsce zaj¹³ G36. Pomimo oficjalnego wycofania ze s³u¿by w Bundeswehrze nadal pozostaje w czêœciowym u¿ytku.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g3_worn">	
		<text>G3A3 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_g36">	
		<text>G36</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g36_descr">	
		<text>G36 to niemiecki karabin automatyczny produkowany przez Heckler &amp; Koch GmbH. Po anulowaniu projektów G11 i G41 w 1986 roku ze wzglêdu na problemy techniczne i logistyczne, niemiecka Bundeswehra pozosta³a z wys³u¿onymi ju¿ karabinami G3. Pora¿ka projektu G11 i zbyt wysoki koszt G41 doprowadzi³y H&K do bankructwa, a nastêpnie wykupienia przez koncern British Aerospace. Pozwoli³o to na rozpoczêcie prac nad nowym karabinem kalibru 5,56x45mm o nazwie fabrycznej HK50. Tym razem u¿yto tañszych tworzyw sztucznych zachowuj¹c jednoczeœnie zalety poprzednich konstrukcji. Dzia³anie HK50 opiera siê na t³oku gazowym o krótkim skoku. Wystrza³ odbywa siê w zamkniêtym zamku ryglowanym przez obrót. Do s³u¿by w Bundeswehrze wprowadzono go w 1995 roku. Znalaz³ siê on równie¿ na wyposa¿eniu wielu zagranicznych jednostek, takich jak brytyjska policja i niektóre amerykañskie jednostki policji. Jak dot¹d nie zg³aszano ¿adnych powa¿nych awarii. Jedyne odnotowane mankamenty to przegrzewaj¹ce siê przy ogniu ci¹³g³ym uchwyty i utrata kalibracji w lunetach wbudowanych w karabiny G36KE. Niektórzy neimieccy ¿o³nierze zg³aszali równie¿ problem z paruj¹cymi szk³ami celowników optycznych w z³ych warunkach pogodowych. Poza wspomnianymi wadami jest to celna, niezawodna i ³atwa w serwisowaniu broñ.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g36_camo">	
		<text>G36 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g36_worn">	
		<text>G36 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_g36k">	
		<text>G36K</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g36k_descr">	
		<text>Krótki wariant karabinu G36 ze skrócon¹ luf¹, wyposa¿ony w t³umik b³yskowy, krótszy jelec i doln¹ szynê monta¿ow¹. Lufa jest niekompatybilna z granatami karabinowymi i nie mo¿na na niej zamontowaæ bagnetu. G36K na wyposa¿eniu niemieckich si³ specjalnych s¹ wyposa¿one w 100-nabojowe magazynki bêbnowe C-Mag. Istniej¹ dwa warianty G-36K. Pierwszy posiada lunetê 3x i górn¹ r¹czkê u³atwiaj¹c¹ przenoszenie. Drugi z kolei posiada celowniki mechaniczne i górn¹ szynê monta¿ow¹.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta G36\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g36k_worn">	
		<text>G36K (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_g3sg1">	
		<text>G3SG/1</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g3sg1_descr">	
		<text>Wersja wyborowa karabinu G3. "SG" oznacza "Scharfschützengewehr", czyli po prostu "karabin wyborowy". Karabiny te zosta³y starannie wyselekcjonowane do modyfikacji spoœród standardowej linii produkcyjnej. Zamontowano na nich lunetê teleskopow¹ Zeiss 1.5-6x na szynie osadzonej na zamku. Kolba zosta³a nieco przed³u¿ona i wyposa¿ona w ciêzki, dwustopniowy bufor i regulowan¹ poduszkê policzkow¹. Dodano te¿ specjalnie dostrojony zespó³ spustowy w celu uzywkania g³adkiego poci¹gniêcia o sile 4,45 N. Zachowano zdolnoœæ prowadzenia ognia ci¹g³ego.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta G3\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g3sg1_modern_descr">	
		<text>Wersja wyborowa karabinu G3. "SG" oznacza "Scharfschutzengewehr", czyli po prostu "karabin wyborowy". Karabiny te zosta³y starannie wyselekcjonowane do modyfikacji spoœród standardowej linii produkcyjnej. Zamontowano na nich lunetê teleskopow¹ Zeiss 1.5-6x na szynie osadzonej na zamku. Kolba zosta³a nieco przed³u¿ona i wyposa¿ona w ciêzki, dwustopniowy bufor i regulowan¹ poduszkê policzkow¹. Dodano te¿ specjalnie dostrojony zespó³ spustowy w celu uzywkania g³adkiego poci¹gniêcia o sile 4,45 N. Zachowano zdolnoœæ prowadzenia ognia ci¹g³ego.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta G3\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g3sg1_worn">	
		<text>G3SG1 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_g43">	
		<text>Karabiner 43</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_g43_descr">	
		<text>Gewehr 43, lub Karabiner 43 to niemiecki karabin samopowtarzalny z okresu II wojny œwiatowej. Zaprojektowano go we wczesnych latach '40 w oparciu na obserwacjach przeprowadzonych na zdobycznych radzieckich karabinach SWT. Wyposa¿ony w lunetê ZF-4 o powiêkszeniu 4x.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta ZF-4\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_famas3"> <!-- NEW GUNS -->		
		<text>FAMAS F3</text>		
	</string>		
	<string id="st_wpn_famas3_descr">		
		<text>FAMAS (Fusil d'Assaut de la Manufacture d'Armes de St-Etienne) to francuski karabin szturmowy zaprojektowany przez firmê zbrojeniow¹ Saint-Étienne. Prace nad karabinem rozpoczêto w roku 1967. Jej autorem jest projektant Paul Tellie. Nowy karabin mia³ zast¹piæ starzej¹ce siê karabiny MAS Modéle 49/56, pistolety maszynowe MAT-49 i karabiny maszynowe MAC Mle.1929. Pierwszy prototyp FAMAS-a zbudowano w 1971 roku. Rok póŸniej dopuszczono go do testów w Armii Francuskiej. W miêdzyczasie Francja przyjê³a tymczasowo do s³u¿by szwajcarski karabin szturmowy SIG SG-540 5.56mm. FAMAS wszed³ do s³u¿by w 1978 roku i od tamtego czasu jest standardowym karabinem Armi Francuskiej, znany wœród ¿o³nierzy jako "Le Clairon" (tr¹bka).\n \n		
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech\n 
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>		
		
	<string id="st_wpn_galil">	
		<text>Galil AR</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_galil_custom">	
		<text>Galil AR (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_galil_descr">	
		<text>Izraelski karabin szturmowy IMI Galil. Kontrukcja bazuje na Fiñskim RK 62, który z kolei wywodzi siê od radzieckiego AK-47. Galil wyró¿nia siê niezawodnoœci¹ w warunkach bojowych oraz ³atwoœci¹ konserwacji. Zaprojektowano go z myœl¹ o s³u¿bie w trudnym, suchym klimacie. Istniej¹ warianty zasilane amunicj¹ kalibru 5.56x45mm oraz 7.62x51mm.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik PBS-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] luneta Galil 4x (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_galil_modern">	
		<text>Galil AR (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_galil_worn">	
		<text>Galil AR (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_gauss">	
		<text>Karabin Gaussa</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_gauss_descr">	
		<text>Karabin Gaussa to eksperymentalna, supercelna broñ zasilana energi¹ artefaktów grawitacyjnych stworzona w sekrecie przez nieznanego projektanta na terenie Zony. Wystrza³ jest niemal nies³yszalny, ze wzglêdu na brak jakiejkolwiek detoancji. Zamiast tego pocisk jest wprawiany w ruch za pomoc¹ supersilnych magnesów. Pomimo niezrównanej z ¿adn¹ inna broni¹ si³y ra¿enia odrzut jest ledwo odczuwalny.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Enhanced 4x scope (integrated)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_glock">	
		<text>Glock 19</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_glock_custom">	
		<text>Glock 19 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_glock_descr">	
		<text>Glock 19 to pomniejszona wersja Glocka 17. Mniejsze gabaryty sprawiaj¹, ¿e  Glock 19 jest bardziej porêczny i ³atwiejszy w ukryciu. Pistolet ten zadebiutowa³ w 1988 roku w Austrii. Glock 19 zachowa³ masê zamka wzglêdem popzednika. Pozwoli³o to na zachowanie w³aœciwoœci odpowiednich do prawid³owego funkcjonowania operacji krótkim odrzutem, skracaj¹c tym samym d³ugoœæ uchwytu i lufy. Oba pistolety maj¹ wiele wspólnych komponentów, w³¹cznie z magazynkiem. \n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik GemTech (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_glock_modern">	
		<text>Glock 19 (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_glock_modern_descr">	
		<text>Glock 19 to pomniejszona wersja Glocka 17. Mniejsze gabaryty sprawiaj¹, ¿e  Glock 19 jest bardziej porêczny i ³atwiejszy w ukryciu. Pistolet ten zadebiutowa³ w 1988 roku w Austrii. Glock 19 zachowa³ masê zamka wzglêdem popzednika. Pozwoli³o to na zachowanie w³aœciwoœci odpowiednich do prawid³owego funkcjonowania operacji krótkim odrzutem, skracaj¹c tym samym d³ugoœæ uchwytu i lufy. Oba pistolety maj¹ wiele wspólnych komponentów, w³¹cznie z magazynkiem. Ten egzemplarz posiada dodatkowy tryb ognia ci¹g³ego.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik GemTech (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_glock_worn">	
		<text>Glock 19 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_grach">	
		<text>MP-443 Gawron</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_grach_descr">	
		<text>MP-443 to produkowany przez I¿ewskie Zak³ady Mechaniczne rosyjski pistolet samopowtarzalny dzia³aj¹cy na zasadzie krótkiego odrzutu lufy. Do testów zg³oszono kilka konstrukcji, sporœród których wygra³ projekt W³adimira Jarygina. W 1993 roku Armia Rosyjska og³osi³a konkurs na nowy pistolet s³u¿bowy. Do testów zg³oszono kilka konstrukcji, sporœród których wygra³ projekt W³adimira Jarygina, który otrzyma³ póŸniej nazwê kodow¹ "Gawron" (ros. ???? / Grach). Wstêpnie oznaczony w indeksie wojskowym jako 6P35, oraz jako MP-443 "Gawron" przez projektanta, zosta³ wprowadzony do s³u¿by w rosyjskiej armii i s³u¿bach porz¹dkowych jako Pistolet Jarygina (PJa).</text>	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_grach_worn">	
		<text>MP-443 Gawron (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_groza">	
		<text>OC-14 Groza</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_descr">	
		<text>OC-14 "Groza" ("Burza") to modularny karabn szturmowy typu bullpup, zasilany nabojem kalibru 9x39mm. Rozwijany we wczesnych latach '90 przez Centralne Biuro Projektowo-Badawcze Broni Sportowej i Myœliwskiej w Tule. Jego przeznaczenie to wszelkiego rodzaju oddzia³y si³ specjalnych Armii Rosyjskiej oraz rosyjskiego MSW, jako broñ do walki w przestrzeniach miejskich. Niewielkie iloœci OC-14 wyprodukowane w latach '90 zosta³y u¿yte w trakcie II Wojny w Czeczeni. Krótko po tym zaprzestano produkcji. Konstrukcja pozwala na zdemontowanie przedniego uchwytu i wymianê na 40-milimetrowy granatnik. OC-14-4A, którego przyjêto do s³u¿by w Specnazie i wojskach frontowych posiada cztery ró¿ne konfiguracje, które mo¿na zmieniaæ w zale¿noœci od misji. Ten egzemplarz posiada granatnik GP-25. \n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] luneta PO 4x34\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany granatnik GP-25\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble">	
		<text>OC-14-1A Groza-1</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble_descr">	
		<text>OC-14-1A to wariant modularnego karabinu "Groza" zasilany nabojem kalibru 7.62x39mm. Szybkostrzelnoœæ, stabilnoœæ pocisku i pojemnoœæ magazynka zosta³y zwiêkszone dziêki u¿yciu l¿ejszego rodzaju amunicji. Grozê-1 produkowano w niewielkich iloœciach.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] luneta PO4x34\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany granatnik GP-25\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_gsh18">	
		<text>GSz-18</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_gsh18_custom">	
		<text>GSz-18 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_gsh18_descr">	
		<text>GSz-18 to rosyjski, samopowtarzalny pistolet kalibru 9x19mm zaprojektowany we wczesnych latach '90 przez KBP Tu³a. Nazwa pistoletu ³¹czy nazwiska swoich projektantów - Griazewa i Szipunowa - a numer 18 oznacza pojemnoœæ magazynka. GSz-18 to konstrukcja dzia³aj¹ca na zasadzie krótkiego odrzutu lufy, o zamkniêtym zamku. Posiada nietypow¹, obrotow¹ lufê wprawian¹ w ruch odrzutem zamka. Wystrza³ odbywa siê za pomoc¹ mechanizmu uderzeniowego. Budowa spustu umo¿liwia utrzymanie owego mechanizmu w stanie napiêtym pomiêdzy wystrza³ami.</text>	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_gsh18_worn">	
		<text>Gsz-18 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_hk416">	
		<text>HK416</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_hk416_descr">	
		<text>HK416 to karabin zaprojektowany i produkowany przez Heckler &amp; Koch jako rozwiniêcie karabinu M4. Jest dostêpny jako kompletny karabin, lub jako górna komora zamkowa kompatybilna z jak¹kolwiek doln¹ komor¹ karabinu typu AR-15. W testach zwi¹zanych z jego produkcj¹ uczestniczy³y amerykañskie oddzia³y Delta Force. Zauwa¿ono wtedy, ¿e system oparty na t³okach znacznie zmniejsza liczbê usterek oraz zwiêksza ¿ywotnoœæ podzespo³ów. Projekt otrzyma³ oznaczenie H&amp;K M4, który zmieniono ze wzglêdu na z³o¿ony przez Colt Defence pozew o naruszenie praw autorskich. Obecnie jest dostêpny jedynie dla s³u¿b rz¹dowych poszczególnych pañstw oraz organizacjmi militarnych.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka: ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik M203\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa">	
		<text>Browning Hi-Power</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_alt">	
		<text>Browning Hi-Power (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_descr">	
		<text>Browning Hi-Power to pistolet kalibru 9mm ze spustem jednooporowym. Jego konstrukcja bazuje na pomys³ach amerykañskiego wynalazcy Johna Browninga. Zosta³ stworzony i opantentowany w roku 1922, nastêpnie patent przej¹³ FN Herstal. Browning zmar³ w roku 1926, przed ukoñczeniem prac nad wersj¹ produkcyjn¹, jednak Dieudonne Saive - projektant z FN - zdo³a³ dokoñczyæ projekt. Hi-Power odnzacza³ siê swoj¹ pojemnoœci¹ magazynka, która wynosi³a 13 nabojów - dwa razy wiêcej, ni¿ inne ówczesne konstrukcje, takie jak Luger, czy Mauser 1910. Ten zmodyfikowany wariant Browninga HP wci¹¿ cieszy siê popularnoœci¹ na ca³ym œwiecie.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 9x19 (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_rusty">	
		<text>Browning Hi-Power (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_rusty_descr">	
		<text>The Browning Hi-Power is a single-action, 9mm semi-automatic pistol. It is based on the ideas of American firearms inventor John Browning, created and patented in 1922, later patented by FN Herstal. Browning died in 1926, before he had finished developing a production version, but FN arms designer Dieudonne Saive fully developed it. The Hi-Power pistol was noted for its 13 round magazine capacity, twice that of contemporary designs such as the Luger or Mauser 1910. This modified variant of the Browning HP pistol, despite its venerable age, enjoys popularity around the world. This model is unreliable due to high amount of corroded metal with dents.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_worn">	
		<text>Browning Hi-Power (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_k98">	
		<text>Karabiner 98 Kurz</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_k98_descr">	
		<text>Kar 98k by³ g³ównym karabinem si³ zbrojnych III Rzeszy w latach 1935 - 1945. Najcelniejsze egzemplarze wyposa¿ono w celowniki teleskopowe ZF39. W rêkach uzdolnionego strzelca by³ w stanie osi¹gn¹æ efektywny zasiêg ostrza³u rzêdu 1000 metrów.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] celownik ZF-4\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_kiparis">	
		<text>OCz-02 Cyprys</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_kiparis_descr">	
		<text>OCz-02 Cyprys (Kiparis) to pistolet maszynowy zaprojektowany w 1972 roku na zamówienie Ministerstwa Obrony ZSRR przez projektantów z Centralnego Biura Projektowo-Badawczego Broni Sportowej w Tule. Uk³ad bazuje na Czechos³owackim pistolecie maszynowym Skorpion Vz.61. Mechanizm automatyczny w OCz-02 jest zasilany odrzutem zamka swobodnego. Wystrza³ odbywa siê z zamkniêtego zamka, co pozytywnie wp³ywa na celnoœæ. W celu zwiêkszenia stabilnoœci zastosowano sk³adan¹ odgórnie kolbê. Nierzadko spotykana broñ w Zonie, najczêœciej na wyposa¿eniu bandytów lub stalkerów, których nie staæ na nic dro¿szego.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 9x19\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_kiparis_worn">	
		<text>OCz-02 Cyprys (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_l85a2">	
		<text>L85A2</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85a2_alt">	
		<text>L85A2 (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85a2_custom">	
		<text>L85A2 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85a2_modern">	
		<text>L85A2 (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85a2_descr">	
		<text>Brytyjski karabin typu bullpup, kalibru 5,56x45mm. Standardowa broñ na wyposa¿eniu Armii Brytyjskiej. Rozwój systemu uzbrojenia SA-80 rozpocz¹³ siê w póŸnych latach '60, gdy Armia Brytyjska zdecydowa³a siê na zast¹pienie starzej¹cego siê ju¿, produkowanego na licencji karabinu FN FAL. Pierwsza iteracja karabinu L85 o oznaczeniu A1 mia³a liczne problemy techniczne. Ulepszony L85A2 okaza³ siê byæ znacznie bardziej niezawodny w warunkach bojowych w zró¿nicowanych klimatach. Wspó³czesne karabiny L85A2 z celownikiem SUSAT s¹ cenione za swoj¹ celnoœæ.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany celownik SUSAT 4x\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_l85">	
		<text>L85A1</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_alt">	
		<text>L85A1 (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_custom">	
		<text>L85A1 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_modern">	
		<text>L85A1 (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_worn">	
		<text>L85A1 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_descr">	
		<text>Brytyjski karabin typu bullpup, kalibru 5,56x45mm. Standardowa broñ na wyposa¿eniu Armii Brytyjskiej. Rozwój systemu uzbrojenia SA-80 rozpocz¹³ siê w póŸnych latach '60, gdy Armia Brytyjska zdecydowa³a siê na zast¹pienie starzej¹cego siê ju¿, produkowanego na licencji karabinu FN FAL. Pierwsza iteracja karabinu L85 o oznaczeniu A1 mia³a liczne problemy techniczne. Zmodernizowany L85A1 okaza³ siê byæ znacznie bardziej niezawodny w warunkach bojowych w zró¿nicowanych klimatach. Wspó³czesne karabiny L85A1 z celownikiem SUSAT s¹ cenione za swoj¹ celnoœæ.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowany celownik SUSAT 4x\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_l96a1">	
		<text>L96A1</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l96a1_descr">	
		<text>Accuracy International Arctic Warfare to karabin wyborowy zaprojektowany przez brytyjsk¹ firmê Accuracy International. Od czasu wprowadzenia w latach '80 zyska³ du¿¹ popularnoœæ wœród cywili, policji i wojska. Konstrukcjê przystosowano do dzia³ania w bardzo niskich temperaturach, zachowuj¹c jednoczeœnie dobre w³aœciwoœci u¿ytkowe w mniej ekstremalnych warnukach.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta Leupold Mark 4\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l96a1_worn">	
		<text>L96A1 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_l96a1m">	
		<text>L96 AWSM</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_l96a1m_descr">	
		<text>Accuracy International Arctic Warfare to karabin wyborowy zaprojektowany przez brytyjsk¹ firmê Accuracy International. Od czasu wprowadzenia w latach '80 zyska³ du¿¹ popularnoœæ wœród cywili, policji i wojska. Konstrukcjê przystosowano do dzia³ania w bardzo niskich temperaturach, zachowuj¹c jednoczeœnie dobre w³aœciwoœci u¿ytkowe w mniej ekstremalnych warnukach. Wersja AWSM jest zasilana nabojem .338 Lapua Magnum.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] zintegrowana luneta Leupold Mark 4\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300">	
		<text>LR-300ML</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_camo">	
		<text>LR-300ML (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_custom">	
		<text>LR-300ML (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_descr">	
		<text>Zaprojektowany na bazie karabinu AR-15, LR-300 to wyœmienity system broni przystosowany do zastosowañ wojskowych, w walce na krótkich dystansach. Posiada sk³adan¹ kolbê szkieletow¹ poprawiaj¹c¹ ergonomiê podczas szybkich szturmów wymagaj¹cych czêsto porêcznej i kompaktowej borni oraz selektywnego trybu ostrza³u. Œwietne w³aœciwoœci ergonomiczne i niska waga czyni¹ go niezwykle celn¹, lecz podatn¹ na zabrudzenia broni¹.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] optyka ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] granatnik M203\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_rusty">	
		<text>LR-300ML (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_rusty_descr">	
		<text>Based on the AR-15, the LR 300 is an excellent weapon system suitable for military use in close quarters battle. Its folding skeletal stock makes it ideal for aggressive and rapid building entries requiring a compact yet powerful selective fire weapon. With excellent ergonomics and lightweight, this weapon is highly accurate but it is sensitive to dirt and is not ideal for difficult field conditions. This model is covered in rust, making it even less reliable in the harsh conditions of the Zone.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_worn">	
		<text>LR-300ML (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m16">	
		<text>M16A4</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m16_descr">	
		<text>The M16 is the U.S. military designation for a family of rifles derived from the ArmaLite AR-15 and further developed by Colt starting in the 1960s. The M16 rifle family including the M16/A1/A2/A3/A4 has been the primary infantry rifle of the United States military since the 1960s. With its variants, it has been in use by 15 NATO countries, and is the most produced firearm in its calibre. The M16 is a lightweight, 5.56x45mm calibre, air cooled, gas operated, magazine fed assault rifle, with a rotating bolt, actuated by direct impingement gas operation. The rifle is made of steel, aluminium, and composite plastics.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m16_worn">	
		<text>M16A4 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a2">	
		<text>M16A2</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a2_descr">	
		<text>The M16A2 rifle entered service in the 1980s, chambered to fire the standard NATO round, the Belgian designed M855/M856 cartridge. The M16A2 is a select fire rifle, incorporating design elements requested by the Marine Corps: an adjustable, windage rear sight, longer stock, heavier barrel, case deflector for left-hand shooters and cylindrical hand guards. The M16A2 is manufactured by Colt and the Fabrique Nationale de Herstal arms company, with the variant rifles made elsewhere in the world.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m24">	
		<text>M24 SWS "Zielony Smok"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m24_descr">	
		<text>A sniper rifle of the US Army, the M24 Sniper Weapon System (SWS) is based on the Remington 700. Fitted with a Leupold 10x40mm scope, the M24 has a stainless steel barrel and an adjustable composite stock made from Kevlar and graphite.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M24 sniper scope (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m249">	
		<text>M249 SAW</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m249_descr">	
		<text>The M249 is a belt fed 5.56x45 machine gun. It is the American adaptation of the Belgian FN Minimi. The M249 has seen action in every major conflict involving the United States since the U.S. invasion of Panama in 1989. Soldiers are generally satisfied with the weapon's performance, though there have been reports of clogging with dirt and sand.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m4">	
		<text>M4A1 RAS</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m4_descr">	
		<text>The M4 Carbine descends from a family of firearms tracing its lineage back to earlier carbine versions of the M16, all based on the original AR-15 made by ArmaLite. It is a shorter and lighter version of the M16 assault rifle, sharing 80% of its parts. The M4 fires 5.56x45mm NATO amunicja and are gas operated, air cooled, magazine fed, selective fire firearms with a 4 position telescoping stock. As with many carbines, the M4 is handy and more convenient to carry than a full length rifle. It has been adopted by United States Special Operations Command (USSOCOM) and is the preferred weapon of the U.S. Army Special Forces and Navy SEALs.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m4_worn">	
		<text>M4A1 RAS (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a1">	
		<text>M4A1</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a1_camo">	
		<text>M4A1 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a1_custom">	
		<text>M4A1 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a1_descr">	
		<text>Ideal for CQC (Close Quarters Combat), the M4A1 carbine is a fully automatic variant of the M16A2 assault rifle. In military use, it has largely replaced the submachine guns firing pistol cartridges that are inadequate against modern body armour. The M4A1 is a modified variant of the M4 carbine able to fire automatic or semi-automatic.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a1_freedom">	
		<text>M4A1 (Kamufla¿ Wolnoœci)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a1_worn">	
		<text>M4A1 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m79">	
		<text>M79</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m79_descr">	
		<text>The M79 grenade launcher is a single shot, shoulder-fired, break-action grenade launcher that fires a 40x46mm grenade, which uses what the US Army calls the High-Low Propulsion System to keep recoil low. First appeared during the Vietnam War.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m98b">	
		<text>Barrett M98B "Bravo"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m98b_descr">	
		<text>The Barrett M98B is a bolt-action sniper rifle chambered in .338 Lapua Mag. Rather than modifying a hunting rifle, Barrett created an original design for the M98B. The M98B features an adjustable stock and cheek pad for comfort, an adjustable trigger for preferable trigger control, a rear monopod and a front bi-pod for stability. Users can further modify the rifle by attaching sights, lights and grips to its rails. The M98B has a simple design making it easy for users to disassemble and clean.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Leupold Mark 4 scope (integrated)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] SR-25 suppressor(wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mosin">	
		<text>Mosin-Nagant</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mosin_descr">	
		<text>A basic version of the Mosin-Nagant with slightly worn interiors. The M1891/30 was produced for standard issue to all Soviet infantry from 1930 to 1945. It was extremely successful in World War II as a sniper rifle when it was equipped with a 4x PE or a 3.5x PU scope.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_purple]• %c[ui_gray_2] PU scope\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mosin_worn">	
		<text>Mosin-Nagant (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mossberg590">	
		<text>Mossberg 590A1</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mossberg590_descr">	
		<text>Mossberg 590 was developed by O.F.Mossberg &amp; sons company during 1970s in US as a modification of the Mossberg model 500 shotgun for adoption by the US Military. Modifications included strengthening of the receiver, installation of the vented heatshield around the barrel, a bayonet lug and extended magazine and an aluminium trigger guard instead of plastic one. Standard finish is Parkerizing, and the gun is provided with replacement pistol grip, which allows easy conversion to 'Cruiser' modification. Since 1987, this was the standard shotgun of US Armed forces; officially replaced in US Army with Benelli M1014 semi-automatic shotgun, Mossberg 590 shotguns are still used by US Navy and US Marine Corp.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mossberg590_worn">	
		<text>Mossberg 590A1 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mp133">	
		<text>MP-133</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp133_descr">	
		<text>The MP-133 is a product of the Izhevsk Mechanical Plant. This shotgun is an evolution of the earlier IZh-81 pump action shotgun, and is intended for civilian and security markets. It is produced in two basic versions: standard MP-133 with tubular magazine and MP-133K with detachable box magazine, both versions can be in various barrel lengths and styles, wood or polymer furniture, fixed or side folding polymer stock or pistol grip only. The MP-133 shotgun uses traditional pump action with sliding forend that has dual action bars. Locking is achieved by a tilting locking piece, installed in the bolt and engages the notch in the barrel extension when in battery. Feed is from tubular underbarrel magazine that holds 4 rounds, though capacity can be enhanced by installing magazine extension tubes.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp133_rusty">	
		<text>MP-133 (rusty)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp133_worn">	
		<text>MP-133 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mp153">	
		<text>MP-153</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp153_descr">	
		<text>The MP-153 self-loading shotgun was the first semi-automatic shotgun designed and manufactured by Izhevsk Mechanical Plant. It was developed along with the pump action MP-133 shotgun and shares many parts and assemblies with it. The MP-153 is one of the most popular semi-automatic shotguns of Russian origin, and is widely used to hunt various games in Russia. It is also sold for export, it is known as Remington "Spartan" SPR-453 autoloader in US. MP-153 shotguns are known for solid but somewhat heavy construction and reliability.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp153_rusty">	
		<text>MP-153 (rusty)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp153_worn">	
		<text>MP-153 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mp412">	
		<text>MP-412 Rex</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp412_descr">	
		<text>The MP412 REX is a Russian double-action .357 magnum revolver with a break-action chamber and an automatic ejector. It was designed for export (REX, Revolver for EXport), but never put into full production due to lack of a market. The weapon was designed by IZHMECH, the state-owned Russian Izhevsk Mechanical Plant, which also designed and produced the Makarov PM semi-automatic pistol.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5">	
		<text>MP5A3</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_alt">	
		<text>MP5A3 (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_custom">	
		<text>MP5A3 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_descr">	
		<text>The MP5 is one of the most famous and wide spread firearms of its class. The MP5's compactness, accuracy and reliability have made it a favourite of numerous military, law enforcement, intelligence and security organisations the world over. The MP5A3 is fitted with a retractable metal stock. Not surprisingly, having flooded the global black markets, it eventually made its way to the Zone.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z 9x19 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_nimble">	
		<text>MP5A3 "Frasier"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_nimble_descr">	
		<text>A submachine gun prototype based on the excellent H&amp;K MP5A3 model. Designed as a next generation close quarter combat weapon, it benefits from a higher calibre, rate of fire and accuracy.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik GemTech (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_worn">	
		<text>MP5A3 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5sd">	
		<text>MP5SD6</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5sd_custom">	
		<text>MP5SD6 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5sd_descr">	
		<text>A variant of the MP5 with an integrated suppressor. In the Zone, mercenaries prefer this variant to the normal one.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632 scopes, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] special MP5SD suppressor (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5sd_new">	
		<text>MP5SD6 (nowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5sd_worn">	
		<text>MP5SD6 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_oc33">	
		<text>OC-33 Pernach</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_oc33_descr">	
		<text>OC-33 "Pernach" (Russian for multivaned mace) is a recent entry into the small class of Russian automatic pistols. The OC-33 is a blowback-operated weapon firing the 9x18mm Makarov pistol cartridge in automatic and semi-automatic mode. The Pernach was developed in 1995 to replace the Stechkin APS pistol in special paramilitary units. Designed in 1995 by Igor Stechkin at the TSKIB SOO, Central Design Bureau for Sporting and Hunting arms, Tula, Russia, the same designer who developed the APS.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] APS suppressor (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_oc33_rusty">	
		<text>OC-33 Pernach (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_oc33_rusty_descr">	
		<text>OC-33 "Pernach" (Russian for multivaned mace) is a recent entry into the small class of Russian automatic pistols. The OC-33 is a blowback-operated weapon firing the 9x18mm Makarov pistol cartridge in automatic and semi-automatic mode. The Pernach was developed in 1995 to replace the Stechkin APS pistol in special paramilitary units. Designed in 1995 by Igor Stechkin at the TSKIB SOO, Central Design Bureau for Sporting and Hunting arms, Tula, Russia, the same designer who developed the APS. Poor safekeeping made this model unreliable.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_oc33_worn">	
		<text>OC-33 Pernach (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_p90">	
		<text>FN P90</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_p90_descr">	
		<text>The FN P90 submachine gun was developed in the late 1980s as a personal defence weapon for troops whose primary activities does not include small arms, such as vehicle and tank crew members, artillery crews etc. Standard pistols and submachine guns were proven ineffective against enemies wearing body armour. FN designers developed a new round, initially designated as SS90, to achieve high penetration while keeping recoil low FN used a small-bore approach, creating a round that looked like the scaled down 5.56 NATO round. The result was FN P90 personal defence weapon, introduced in 1990 along with improved 5.7x28 SS190 amunicja which replaced polymer cored bullets with heavier dual core, steel and aluminium, bullets for better penetration against body armour.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 5.7x28 compatible suppressor</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_pb">	
		<text>PB</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pb_custom">	
		<text>PB (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pb_descr">	
		<text>The PB (Pistolet Besshumnyj or Silent Pistol), also known in the Soviet army as 6P9, has been developed in 1967 for Spetsnaz units of the Soviet Army, as well as for KGB operatives. The pistol is based on a modified Makarov PM pistol and features an unique integral two part suppressor. Issued into service in 1967, the PB (GRAU index 6P9) is a Soviet silenced pistol based on the Makarov PM. It was intended for use by the KGB and army reconnaissance groups. The front part of the suppressor is detachable, so that the pistol can be broken down into two parts for convenient carry. The PB's integral suppressor also reduces the bullet velocity to below subsonic levels.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 6P9 suppressor (integrated)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pb_worn">	
		<text>PB (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_pkm_zulus">	
		<text>PKM Zulusa</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pkm_zulus_descr">	
		<text>This weapon was previously owned by Zulu. Its special features include an enlarged ammo box and a particularly reliable retracting mechanism design. The modifications meant an increase in the weapon's weight, but that wasn't a problem for the last owner.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-1S-03 Kobra sight (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_pkp">	
		<text>PKP Pieczenieg</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pkp_descr">	
		<text>The PKP "Pieczenieg" is a Russian light machine gun chambered for the 7.62x54mmR round. It is a modernised PKM machine gun. The Pieczenieg is said to be more accurate than all its predecessors due to a heavier, non-removable, forced air cooling barrel with radial cooling ribs and a handle which eliminates the haze effect from hot gases and keeps the barrel cooler, making the weapon more reliable.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_pm">	
		<text>PM</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_actor">	
		<text>Ceremonialny Makarow PM</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_actor_descr">	
		<text>An ancient PM given to Degtyarev as a reward for "Successful execution of highly dangerous state orders, as well as valour and courage shown in the line of duty".</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_custom">	
		<text>PM (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_descr">	
		<text>This Soviet legacy is the most common pistol in the Zone and is one of the best compact self-defence handguns available. It is small, highly reliable, easy to use and maintain in working order. It also suffers from several drawbacks, including short range, low firing accuracy and poor stopping power, while also losing out to modern pistols in its class in terms of weight and magazine size. In 1951, the Pistol Makarova was selected because of its simplicity, easy manufacturing, accuracy, and reasonable stopping power.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_rusty">	
		<text>PM (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_rusty_descr">	
		<text>This Soviet legacy is the most common pistol in the Zone and is one of the best compact self-defence handguns available. It is small, highly reliable, easy to use and maintain in working order. It also suffers from several drawbacks, including short range, low firing accuracy and poor stopping power, while also losing out to modern pistols in its class in terms of weight and magazine size. In 1951, the Pistol Makarova was selected because of its simplicity, easy manufacturing, accuracy, and reasonable stopping power. Rust has made this model considerably less reliable</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_worn">	
		<text>PM (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_pmm">	
		<text>PMM</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pmm_descr">	
		<text>The most widely known variant, the Makarov PMM was a redesign of the original gun. In 1990 a group of engineers reworked the original Makarov, primarily by increasing the load for the cartridge. The result is 25% more gas pressure increasing in prêdkoœæ wylotowa. The PMM magazine holds 12 rounds, compared to the PM's 8 rounds.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_pp2000">	
		<text>PP-2000</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_pp2000_descr">	
		<text>The PP-2000 is the latest development of the Instrument Design Bureau (KBP) from Tula, Russia. First displayed to the public in 2004, the patent for its layout has been filed in 2001 and was issued in 2003. The niche for the PP-2000 is a personal defence weapon for non-infantry military personnel, as well as close combat weapon for special forces and special law enforcement teams. As such, it is a compact weapon with few parts for reliability, simplified maintenance and low cost. Best suited for close combat.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 9x19 compatible \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41">	
		<text>PPSz-41</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41_new">	
		<text>PPSz-41 (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41_camo">	
		<text>PPSz-41 (kamufla¿)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41_old">	
		<text>PPSz-41 (stary)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41_rusty">	
		<text>PPSz-41 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41_worn">	
		<text>PPSz-41 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41_descr">	
		<text>A major infantry weapon of the Soviet armed forces during World War II, the PPSz-41 was a durable, low-maintenance weapon made of cheap, easily-obtained components. They utilise 7.62x25mm cartridge.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta">	
		<text>Armsel Protecta</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_aim">	
		<text>Armsel Protecta (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_aim_descr">	
		<text>The uniquely designed Armsel Protecta is a rotating cylinder fed 12-gauge shotgun developed for riot control and combat. Antiquated now by the Russian Sajga 12 and the American AA-12, the Protecta was a revolutionary weapon created by the Apartheid government in the 1980s. This smoothbore combat revolver-type shotgun was intended to provide extreme firepower for militarised units. The weapon benefits from a large magazine and a high effective rate of fire, but its bulkiness and considerable weight, combined with a long czas prze³adowania, are the price to be paid for these advantages. Rare in the Zone and used primarily to clear confined spaces of mutants. Specifically this variant is highly modernised, details inside are tightly fit to each other, muzzle energy is increased significantly thanks to higher pressure in the gun barrel. Sacrificing rate of fire, stopping power is increased. This model has Aimpoint AB collimator sight made by Swedish company.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] "Aimpoint" sight (integrated)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_camo">	
		<text>Armsel Protecta (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_custom">	
		<text>Armsel Protecta (zmodyfikowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_descr">	
		<text>The uniquely designed Armsel Protecta is a rotating cylinder fed 12-gauge shotgun developed for riot control and combat. Antiquated now by the Russian Sajga 12 and the American AA-12, the Protecta was a revolutionary weapon created by the Apartheid government in the 1980s. This smoothbore combat revolver-type shotgun was intended to provide extreme firepower for militarised units. The weapon benefits from a large magazine and a high effective rate of fire, but its bulkiness and considerable weight, combined with a long czas prze³adowania, are the price to be paid for these advantages. Rare in the Zone and used primarily to clear confined spaces of mutants.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_nimble">	
		<text>Armsel Protecta (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_nimble_descr">	
		<text>The uniquely designed Armsel Protecta is a rotating cylinder fed 12-gauge shotgun developed for riot control and combat. Antiquated now by the Russian Sajga 12 and the American AA-12, the Protecta was a revolutionary weapon created by the Apartheid government in the 1980s. This smoothbore combat revolver-type shotgun was intended to provide extreme firepower for militarised units. The weapon benefits from a large magazine and a high effective rate of fire, but its bulkiness and considerable weight, combined with a long czas prze³adowania, are the price to be paid for these advantages. Rare in the Zone and used primarily to clear confined spaces of mutants. According to certain sources, this model once belonged to Tank, but little is known about him.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_rusty">	
		<text>Armsel Protecta (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_worn">	
		<text>Armsel Protecta (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_rg6">	
		<text>RG-6</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_rg6_descr">	
		<text>The RG-6 (index 6G30) was in development between 1993 and 1994 by the TSKIB SOO. The new stand-alone, rapid-firing multi-shot launcher was required to increase the firepower of the infantry during the urban combat, due to recent small scale conflicts, such as the Chechen Wars. The RG-6 entered limited production by mid-1990s and is now in use by various elements of the Russian Army and special forces, as well as by special forces in MVD (Internal Affairs Ministry). The RG-6 is designed to fire all standard 40mm caseless grenades, available for general issue underbarrel launchers, such as GP-25 and GP-30. These rounds include VOG-25 fragmentation grenade, VOG-25P bouncing fragmentation grenade and "Gvozd" (Nail) nonlethal tear gas grenade for riot control. The drum is also front-loaded. Widely used for rapid suppression of enemy firing positions and, when in the open, attacking defended fixed targets or fighting particularly tough mutants.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_rp">	
		<text>PKM</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_rp_descr">	
		<text>Fitted with a skeleton buttstock made from wood as well as a hinged buttplate and a wooden pistol grip. The rear part of the buttstock houses a cleaning kit, and a disassembled cleaning rod is stored in the right leg of the bipod. A very reliable machine gun.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_rpd">	
		<text>RPD</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_rpd_descr">	
		<text>The RPD (Degtyaryov hand-held machine gun) is a light machine gun developed in the Soviet Union by Vasily Degtyaryov for the intermediate 7.62x39mm M43 cartridge.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_rpg7">	
		<text>RPG-7</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_rpg7_descr">	
		<text>The RPG-7 is a further development of the previous RPG-2 anti-tank grenade launcher. The RPG-7, in its first version, known as RPG-7V, has been adopted by the Soviet army in 1961, and is still fielded in Russia and at least 50 more countries. By far, RPG-7 can be considered as one of the most successful anti-tank grenade launchers ever made. Initially thought of as an anti-armour weapon, it was later adopted for other fire support missions with the introduction of other types of grenades, such as anti-infantry HE-FRAG and multi-purpose Thermobaric/FAE. The RPG-7 is a shoulder fired, single shot, smoothbore recoilless launcher, grenades are loaded from the front, and the rear of the barrel is fitted with venturi nozzle. Due to the recoilless design, the backblast is dangerous. The RPG-7 is usually issued with 2.7X fixed magnification optical sight, designated PGO-7. It is a simple and inexpensive, but possess a high threat to modern tanks and can also serve in a number of other roles, making it a flexible weapon.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_rpk">	
		<text>RPK</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_rpk_descr">	
		<text>The RPK is a Soviet light machine gun, developed by Mikhail Kalashnikov in 1961 based on the Kalashnikov assault rifle. Created as part of Soviet efforts to standardise the armoury of the Red Army, the RPK replaced the RPD and is still in use to present day.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_rpk_worn">	
		<text>RPK (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_rpk74">	
		<text>RPK-74N</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_rpk74_descr">	
		<text>The RPK (Ruchnoy Pulemyot Kalashnikova or Kalashnikov hand-held machine gun) is a 5.45x45mm light machine gun, developed by Mikhail Kalashnikov in the late 1950s. It was created as part of a program designed to standardise the small arms inventory of the Red Army, where it replaced the 7.62x39mm RPD light machine gun. Today, the RPK continues to be used by the armed forces of countries of the former Soviet Union and certain African and Asian nations. The Polish Army adopted the weapon in 1974, where it is used in airborne assault, reconnaissance and special operations units. The RPK was also manufactured under license in Bulgaria and Romania.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 scopes \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik TGP-A\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_rpk74_worn">	
		<text>RPK-74N (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_saiga12s">	
		<text>Sajga 12S</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_saiga12s_descr">	
		<text>The Sajga 12 is a Kalashnikov pattern, 12 gauge combat shotgun, manufactured by Izhmash. The Sajga 12 is recognizable by its Kalashnikov design with the large lever safety on the right side of the receiver, the optic mounting rail on the left and the large top mounted dust cover held in place by the rear of the recoil spring assembly. Earning respect in the Zone for its lethality, it is intended for engaging targets at short range (50 metres or less) or in confined spaces.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] PBS-1\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_saiga12s_worn">	
		<text>Sajga 12S (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_scar">	
		<text>FN SCAR-H</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_scar_custom">	
		<text>FN SCAR-H (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_scar_descr">	
		<text>The Special Operations Forces Combat Assault Rifle (SCAR) is a modular rifle made by FN Herstal for SOCOM to satisfy the requirements of the SCAR competition. This family of rifle consist of two types, the SCAR-H and SCAR-L. The SCAR-H (Heavy) is chambered in 7.62x51mm NATO cartridge.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_scar_new">	
		<text>FN SCAR-H (nowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_scar_worn">	
		<text>FN SCAR-H (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220">	
		<text>SIG P220</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_custom">	
		<text>SIG P220 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_descr">	
		<text>The SIG-Sauer P220, manufactured in the late 1970s by J.P. Sauer &amp; Son Company, is often considered the best out of the box .45 calibre double action pistol. An instant success, the P220 was adopted by the Swiss and Japanese SDF and by many European police organisations. This pistol also found its way into the US, first through the Browning Arms Company of Utah and since the 1980s, through the SIGARMS Company of New Hampshire.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] .45 ACP Suppressor</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_nimble">	
		<text>SIG P220 "Alpine"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_nimble_descr">	
		<text>A unique model of the SIG-Sauer P220 handgun. Part of a small limited edition made for an unidentified special forces unit. The model benefits from an increased magazine capacity, a high durability steel barrel and an ultra-durable polymer receiver.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] .45 ACP Suppressor</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_rusty">	
		<text>SIG P220 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_rusty_descr">	
		<text>The SIG-Sauer P220, manufactured in the late 1970s by J.P. Sauer &amp; Son Company, is often considered the best out of the box .45 calibre double action pistol. An instant success, the P220 was adopted by the Swiss and Japanese SDF and by many European police organisations. This pistol also found its way into the US, first through the Browning Arms Company of Utah and since the 1980s, through the SIGARMS Company of New Hampshire. This model is covered in rust, resulting in lower combat effectiveness.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_worn">	
		<text>SIG P220 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550">	
		<text>SIG SG550</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_camo">	
		<text>SIG SG550 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_custom">	
		<text>SIG SG550 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_descr">	
		<text>Renowned for its high production quality and good performance, the SG 550 is often referred to as the finest 5.56 mm rifle ever made. It has a side-folding skeletonised buttstock and a lightweight aluminium bipod that folds into grooves in the lower handguard.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_rusty">	
		<text>SIG SG550 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_rusty_descr">	
		<text>Renowned for its high production quality and good performance, the SG 550 is often referred to as the finest 5.56 mm rifle ever made. It has a side-folding skeletonised buttstock and a lightweight aluminium bipod that folds into grooves in the lower handguard. This model is covered in rust, resulting in lower combat effectiveness.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_sniper">	
		<text>SIG SG550-1 Wyborowy</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_sniper_descr">	
		<text>A marksman variant of a popular Swiss-made assault rifle, the SG 550-S constitutes a perfect middle ground between sniper and assault rifles, retaining the strong points of both types of weaponry. On the other hand, it suffers from certain drawbacks such as being somewhat lacking in stopping power and accuracy for a sniper rifle and lack of automatic fire. Still, it remains one of the best top-tier weapon systems available within the Exclusion Zone.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Kahles ZF95 scope (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok">	
		<text>SIG SG550 Strza³a</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok_descr">	
		<text>A Swiss made SIG SG-550 assault rifle. Although it isn't new, it is clear that the previous owner took good care of it: the weapon has been taken apart and put back together with every component fine-tuned for optimum performance, increasing stopping power. The letter "S" has been carved into the stock, along with 16 small notches.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_worn">	
		<text>SIG SG550 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_sig552">	
		<text>SIG SG552 Commando</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig552_descr">	
		<text>The SG 552 Commando is designed for urban combat, making it the most compact member of SIG's renowned SG 550 family, which enhances its CQC capabilities.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sig552_worn">	
		<text>SIG SG552 Commando (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_sks">	
		<text>SKS</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sks_descr">	
		<text>The SKS is one of the first weapons chambered for the 7.62x39mm round. Replaced in Soviet front-line service by the AK-47 in the early 1950s, it remained in second-line service for decades and is still used as a ceremonial arm today.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_purple]• %c[ui_gray_2] PU scope\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sks_modern">	
		<text>SKS (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sks_worn">	
		<text>SKS (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12">	
		<text>SPAS-12</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_custom">	
		<text>SPAS-12 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_descr">	
		<text>The SPAS-12 is a dual-mode shotgun, designed for combat and anti-riot measures. It is employed by many special military and police units around the world. With its distinctive heat shield and folding stock, the SPAS-12 is an iconic firearm. Notable for its reliability and tactical flexibility. Despite its heavy weight, complex mechanism and considerable cost, it is in demand in the Zone due to its effectiveness against mutants.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_nimble">	
		<text>SPAS-12 (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_nimble_descr">	
		<text>An army shotgun designed specifically for assault units and created on the basis of the Franchi SPAS-12. Capable of automatic fire like its predecessor, but provides better recoil compensation thanks to a balanced shock free system. Capable of automatic fire like its predecessor, but provides better recoil compensation thanks to a balanced shock free system.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_rusty">	
		<text>SPAS-12 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_worn">	
		<text>SPAS-12 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_sr25">	
		<text>SR-25</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sr25_descr">	
		<text>The SR-25, Stoner Rifle, model 25 was developed by Reed Knight, owner of Knights Armament Co. and Eugene Stoner. The SR-25 is an AR-15 rifle scaled up to shoot 7.62x51mm NATO or .308 amunicja. 60% of parts in the rifle is interchangeable with AR-15 components. This rifle sold well among civilian shooters who needed an accurate semi-automatic rifle in 7.62x51mm NATO or .308 calibre for hunting or target shooting. This rifle also found a favour in US Military. All rifles built on the SR-25 platform share the same basic action, the AR-15/M16 system. Because of AR-15 style recoil buffer, which extends rearwards from the receiver, SR-25 cannot be fitted with a folding stock instead it is fitted with telescoping stock.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] SR-25 special \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Leupold Mark 4 scope (integrated)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 grenade launcher\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_sv98">	
		<text>SW-98</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sv98_custom">	
		<text>SW-98 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sv98_descr">	
		<text>The SV-98 (Snaiperskaya Vintovka Model 1998) is a Russian bolt action sniper rifle designed by Vladimir Stronskiy. In 2003 special operations troops were armed with the 7.62 mm 6S11 sniper system comprising the SV-98 sniper rifle (index 6V10) and 7N14 sniper enhanced penetration round. The rifle has been used in combat during operations in Chechnya.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] PKS-07 scope (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_sv98_worn">	
		<text>SW-98 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_svd">	
		<text>SWD</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_custom">	
		<text>SWD (customised)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_descr">	
		<text>Originally intended for designated marksmen in every basic Soviet infantry unit, the Dragunov SVD was not designed for specialised sniper teams. Relatively light for a sniper rifle but well-balanced and having semiautomatic fire, its precision is good but not exceptional. It has an effective range of up to 800 metres.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] KZRZP suppressor (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble">	
		<text>SWD "Ryœ"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble_descr">	
		<text>A hand-assembled version of the SVDm-2 sniper rifle with improved mechanisms for increased flatness. Little difference in appearance, but provides an ideal combination of accuracy and stopping power.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 1P59 "Hyperon" scope (integrated)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] KZRZP \n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_rusty">	
		<text>SWD (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_rusty_descr">	
		<text>Originally intended for designated marksmen in every basic Soviet infantry unit, the Dragunov SVD was not designed for specialised sniper teams. Relatively light for a sniper rifle but well-balanced and having semiautomatic fire, its precision is good but not exceptional. It has an effective range of up to 800 metres. This variant is in bad condition, which results in higher misfire probability.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_worn">	
		<text>SWD (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_svt40">	
		<text>SWT-40</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svt40_descr">	
		<text>The SWT-40 is a surplus semi-automatic rifle chambered in the 7.62x54mmR round. It saw widespread use in the Red Army and Wehrmacht during WWII.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_purple]• %c[ui_gray_2] PU special scope\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svt40_modern">	
		<text>SWT-40 (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svt40_rusty">	
		<text>SWT-40 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svt40_worn">	
		<text>SWT-40 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_svu">	
		<text>OC-03 SWU</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_alt">	
		<text>OC-03 SWU (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_descr">	
		<text>The OC-03 SWU is a rare, compact version of the SVD sniper rifle, created for use by the airborne infantry, but later employed mainly by the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs. The main difference between it and the SVD is it's compact size and thus improved handling, thanks to a bullpup configuration and shortened barrel, making it sought after by stalkers in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble">	
		<text>OC-03A SWU-A</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble_descr">	
		<text>The SWU-A is a variant of the SWU rifle capable of automatic fire, designed on a request from the Russian Interior Ministry. Although the weapon is generally not suited for close-combat situations, the automatic fire has proven itself to be a reliable emergency solution for exposed marksmen. This particular model of SVU-A used to belong to Max, the legendary guardian of Freedom.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_worn">	
		<text>OC-03 SWU (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_toz194">	
		<text>TOZ-194</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz194_descr">	
		<text>The TOZ-194 is a 12 Gauge, pump action shotgun manufactured by the Tula Arms Plant. Designed during the last years of the Soviet Union, the manufacture of this firearm has started after its collapse, and since then it has gained a certain popularity within civilian shooters in Russia and in Europe and is reported to be in use with some Russian Security forces.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz194_rusty">	
		<text>TOZ-194 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz194_worn">	
		<text>TOZ-194 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34">	
		<text>TOZ-34</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_custom">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_decor">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (grawerowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_descr">	
		<text>Intended for professional and amateur hunting the TOZ-34 is an over/under shotgun. Though lacking in capacity, only 2 rounds, it compares well with high-grade shotguns due to its high accuracy of hits. The TOZ 34 was designed by N. I. Korovyakov and V. P. Ochnev in 1965. Affordable in price, with high damage output and its ability to unload both rounds instantly make it a popular weapon among rookies on the outskirts of the Zone. Especially useful against mutants thanks to its accuracy and stopping power.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_bull">	
		<text>TOZ-34 "Byk"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_bull_descr">	
		<text>Hand made modification of TOZ-34 that uses only specially made "Bull" amunicja that could probably stop a tank. Modifications are mostly related to the strength of the gun, and at a first glance, it looks simply like a decorated TOZ-34. But when you take a closer look, you can see that barrel is made from a unique metal, betraying its non-standard origin, and the stock is also made from some type of carbon fibre, inscribed with the letter "F". It's hard to tell who made it and how it ended up in the Zone... \n \n%c[ui_gray_2]</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_mark4">	
		<text>TOZ-34 "Bizon"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_mark4_descr">	
		<text>Intended for professional and amateur hunting the TOZ-34 is an over/under shotgun. Though lacking in capacity, only 2 rounds, it compares well with high-grade shotguns due to its high accuracy of hits. The TOZ 34 was designed by N. I. Korovyakov and V. P. Ochnev in 1965. Affordable in price, with high damage output and its ability to unload both rounds instantly make it a popular weapon among rookies on the outskirts of the Zone. Especially useful against mutants thanks to its accuracy and stopping power. This model has a Leupold Mark 4 scope attached to it.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Luneta Leupold Mark 4 (zintegrowana)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_obrez">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (obrzyn)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_obrez_custom">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (dostosowany obrzyn)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_obrez_decor">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (grawerowany obrzyn)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_obrez_descr">	
		<text>Intended for professional and amateur hunting the TOZ-34 is a over/under shotgun. Modifications made to this gun by removing much of the barrel and the stock makes this shotgun more compact and easier to carry. Popular among rookies and bandits as they can hide it easily in their trench coats.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_obrez_rusty">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (zardzewia³y obrzyn) </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_obrez_worn">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (u¿ywany obrzyn)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_rusty">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_worn">	
		<text>TOZ-34 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_trg_descr">	
		<text>The TRG-42 is not an accurised version of an existing rifle, but was developed from the very beginning as a sniper rifle. Its consistent high accuracy and reliability have made it popular both in long-range competitions and military sniper operations.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] luneta FINDOT (zintegrowana)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_tt33">	
		<text>TT-33</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_tt33_modern">	
		<text>TT-33 (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_tt33_rusty">	
		<text>TT-33 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_tt33_worn">	
		<text>TT-33 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_type63">	
		<text>Typ 63</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_type63_descr">	
		<text>The Type 63, often incorrectly referred to as Type 68 by Western sources, is a Chinese-designed rifle with a resemblance to the SKS. However, the weapon uses a rotating bolt working system from the AK-47 rifle instead of the tilting bolt system of the SKS.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] PU scope\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_ump45">	
		<text>UMP45</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ump45_custom">	
		<text>UMP45 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ump45_descr">	
		<text>The UMP was developed by H&amp;K in the 1990s, first appearing on the market in 1999. The idea behind the UMP was to create lightweight and powerful submachine gun, that was also cheaper than the MP5. The UMP, being targeted primarily for US law enforcement, appeared in .45ACP and .40SW chamberings, and later in 9mm. Providing greater stopping power than the MP5, the UMP45 also produces more recoil. This makes controlling full automatic fire more difficult. The UMP45's cyclic rate of fire was lowered significantly to combat this problem.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Gemtech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ump45_worn">	
		<text>UMP45 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_usas12">	
		<text>USAS-12</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usas12_descr">	
		<text>The Daewoo Precision Industries USAS-12 (Universal Sports Automatic Shotgun 12 gauge) is an automatic shotgun designed for combat manufactured in South Korea by Daewoo Precision Industries in 1980s. How a Korean gun made it into Ukraine is something stalkers would very much like to know. Maybe there's a K2 rifle out there.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_usp">	
		<text>USP45</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_alt">	
		<text>USP45 (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_custom">	
		<text>USP45 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_descr">	
		<text>Originally designed for the American market, the USP, Universal Self loading Pistol, is known as an accurate and reliable handgun. U.S. law enforcement and military provided much of the design criteria for the USP. The controls are uniquely American, influenced by famous designs like the Government Model 1911 pistol. All USPs use a fibre-reinforced polymer frame stiffened by stainless steel inserts at areas subject to stress and friction. Incorporating several successful handgun design elements, the USP Compact .45 is a part of the USP family of handguns designed by H&amp;K. Able to withstand extreme punishment and adverse conditions, it is used by several countries' police and special forces units.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] .45 ACP suppressor (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_match">	
		<text>USP Match</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_match_descr">	
		<text>An enhanced USP by HK with distinct characteristics that make it more attractive to the target shooter. With the O-Ring barrel first seen in the Mark 23, the Match includes compensator that helps reduce the relatively mild kick of the 9x19. The Match also features polygonal rifling, a trigger stop, and fully adjustable rear sight.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik GemTech (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_nimble">	
		<text>USP "Marsz"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_nimble_descr">	
		<text>A compact, large calibre pistol with short bolt movement and lightweight bolt assembly. Used to belong to a mercenary called Wolfhound. Appears to be a modified USP Compact pistol.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik GemTech (wymaga modyfikacji)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_worn">	
		<text>USP45 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_val">	
		<text>AS Wa³</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_val_descr">	
		<text>The AS Val is widely used by Russian Army recon units, as well as by MVD (Internal Affairs Ministry) and FSB (Federal Security Bureau) Special Forces. The AS-VAL is a gas operated, integrally suppressed weapon. The receiver is machined from steel forging for improved strength. It has a standard side-mounted rail for optical, night vision or red dot scopes but has no provision for mounting a bayonet or a grenade launcher. The integral suppressor could be easily detached for maintenance, repair, or compact storage, but the rifle should not be fired with the suppressor removed due to safety and reliability issues.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29,  PSO-1M2-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] VSS suppressor (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_val_modern">	
		<text>AS Wa³ (wspó³czesny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_val_modern_descr">	
		<text>The AS Val is widely used by Russian Army recon units, as well as by MVD (Internal Affairs Ministry) and FSB (Federal Security Bureau) Special Forces. The AS-VAL is a gas operated, integrally suppressed weapon. The receiver is machined from steel forging for improved strength. It has a standard side-mounted rail for optical, night vision or red dot scopes but has no provision for mounting a bayonet or a grenade launcher. The integral suppressor could be easily detached for maintenance, repair, or compact storage, but the rifle should not be fired with the suppressor removed due to safety and reliability issues.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] VSS suppressor (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_val_worn">	
		<text>AS Wa³ (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_vepr12">	
		<text>Wepr-12 "M³ot"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vepr12_descr">	
		<text>The Vepr-12 is a multi-purpose semi-automatic shotgun, created by Molot-Oruzhie Ltd. It is patterned after Kalashnikov rifles, and built on the heavy RPK light machine gun receiver. Like the Kalashnikov rifle, it is a rotating bolt, gas operated gun that feeds from a 10 round magazine.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] PBS-1 \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_vihr">	
		<text>SR-3M Wichr</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vihr_descr">	
		<text>The SR-3 "Vikhr" ("Whirlwind") compact assault rifle was developed in CNIITochMash and manufactured by Tula Arms Plant. Initially known as "MA" (Malogabaritnyj Avtomat - small size assault rifle), it was based on the suppressed 9x39mm AS-Val assault rifle, and intended for concealed carry by special VIP protection teams and State Security operatives, SR3M Vikhr is result of combining the qualities of SR-3, AS VAL and VSS Vintorez. SR-3M also has a larger capacity of 30 rounds, which also provides more reliable feeding during automatic fire.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, PSO-1M2-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] SR-3M \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez">	
		<text>VSS Wintorez</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_1pn93_descr">	
		<text>Designed at TsNIITochMash by Peter Serdyukov and his team, the new rifle was intended for various Spetsnaz troops of the Soviet Army, KGB and MVD. The VSS is quite popular among its users for its stealthy capabilities and the great lethality of the heavy 9x39mm bullets. The effective range of the VSS is limited to 300-400 metres. Standard sighting equipment consists of side rail on the receiver, which usually accommodates the 4x  PSO-1M2-1 scope. Any other scope or night vision sight can be mounted on the appropriate mount. Backup iron sights consist of tangent rear and blade front. The rear sight is graduated for up to 400 metres.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 1PN93 "Tot" scope (integrated)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] VSS suppressor (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_alt">	
		<text>VSS Wintorez (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_descr">	
		<text>Designed at TsNIITochMash by Peter Serdyukov and his team, the new rifle was intended for various Spetsnaz troops of the Soviet Army, KGB and MVD. The VSS is quite popular among its users for its stealthy capabilities and the great lethality of the heavy 9x39mm bullets. The effective range of the VSS is limited to 300-400 metres. Standard sighting equipment consists of side rail on the receiver, which usually accommodates the 4x  PSO-1M2-1 scope. Any other scope or night vision sight can be mounted on the appropriate mount. Backup iron sights consist of tangent rear and blade front. The rear sight is graduated for up to 400 metres.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1M2-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] VSS suppressor (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble">	
		<text>VSS Wintorez "Fala"</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble_descr">	
		<text>A special variant of the famous VSS sniper rifle. This model has been extensively customised. Its internal mechanism has been replaced with a better one, which results in increased prêdkoœæ wylotowa and accuracy. It has an effective range of up to 600 metres.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] PSO-1 scope (integrated)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] VSS suppressor (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_worn">	
		<text>VSS Wintorez (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_vityaz">	
		<text>PP-19-01 WitiaŸ</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vityaz_descr">	
		<text>A variant of PP-19 with 30-round magazine chambered for 9x19mm, designed in 2004. It is used by patrol groups, Russian traffic police, Russian security police, and by units of the MVD.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] PBS-1 \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_vsk94">	
		<text>VSK-94</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vsk94_descr">	
		<text>The VSK-94 is a 9x39mm suppressed sniper rifle developed by the Russian KBP Instrument Design Bureau as a low-cost alternative to the VSS rifle. The rifle is based on the 9A-91 carbine. The VSK-94 was designed to accurately engage unarmoured targets at ranges up to 400m.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1M2-1 \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 9A-91/VSK-94 suppressor (integrated)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vsk94_worn">	
		<text>VSK-94 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_vssk">	
		<text>VSSK Wych³op</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vssk_descr">	
		<text>The VSSK is a Russian bullpup, straight-pull bolt-action sniper rifle chambered for the 12.7x55mm subsonic round. The weapon is also known by its other name, Vykhlop. It was developed in 2002 for special forces units of FSB.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] PKS-07 scope (integrated)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_vz61">	
		<text>Skorpion vz.61</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vz61_alt">	
		<text>Skorpion vz.61 (alternatywny)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vz61_camo">	
		<text>Skorpion vz.61 (zakamuflowany)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vz61_descr">	
		<text>Originally chambered for .32 ACP when adopted by the Czechoslovak Army in 1961, mass production of the Skorpion vz. 68 never took place. Even so, a large number of pre-production vz. 68 models made their way into the Zone. \n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z 9x19 (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vz61_freedom">	
		<text>Skorpion vz.61 (Kamufla¿ Wolnoœci)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vz61_rusty">	
		<text>Skorpion vz.61 (zardzewia³y)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vz61_rusty_descr">	
		<text>Originally chambered for .32 ACP when adopted by the Czechoslovak Army in 1961, mass production of the Skorpion vz. 68 never took place. Even so, a large number of pre-production vz. 68 models made their way into the Zone. This rusty model is less reliable and it's impossible to attach a suppressor to it.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] mounting suppressor is not possible\n \n</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_vz61_worn">	
		<text>Skorpion vz.61 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_walther">	
		<text>Walther P99</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_walther_custom">	
		<text>Walther P99 (niestandardowy)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_walther_descr">	
		<text>Ergonomics being a key focus in its design, the Walther P99 is a recoil-operated pistol with a fibreglass polymer frame. Developed for law enforcement and the civilian shooting market, it's employed by police units in a number of countries.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z 9x19</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_walther_worn">	
		<text>Walther P99 (u¿ywany)</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="wpn_tt33_descr">	
		<text>The TT-33 is a Russian 7.62x25mm pistol. It was developed in the early 1930s by Fedor Tokarev as a service pistol for the Soviet military to replace the Nagant M1895 revolver. Many communist or Soviet bloc countries made a variation of the TT-33 pistol, until it was eventually replaced by 9x18mm Makarov PM in 1952. Production of the TT-33 in the USSR ended in 1954.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel">	
		<text>Niezidentyfikowana broñ</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel_descr">	
		<text>An unknown weapon, the firing mechanism of which has not been established. The weapon appears faulty - squeezing the trigger doesn't do anything. It's very heavy and definitely high-tech. Of note is that it appears not to fire bullets based on ignition. Most probably, the rounds are propelled by electro-magnetic forces. One can only suspect what kind of destructive potential it possesses.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<!-- New -->	
	<string id="st_wpn_ash12">	
		<text>ASz-12.7</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_ash12_descr">	
		<text>The ASh-12.7 (ÀØ-12.7, which stands for "Àâòîìàò øòóðìîâîé 12.7ìì" or "Automatic assault rifle, 12.7mm") battle rifle is a dedicated CQB/Urban Operations weapon, developed by TsKIB SOO ("Central Design and Research Bureau of Sporting and Hunting Arms"), a subsidiary of the KBP Instrument Design Bureau of Tula, Russia, by request from the Russian FSB (Federal Security Service). The weapon was designed with extreme short-range stopping power in mind because it is intended for special units of the FSB which operate in urban environments against heavily armed and organized gangsters and terrorists who need to be killed in one shot. According to the Russian press, the first batch of ASh-12.7 assault rifles was delivered to the FSB.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, C-more Railway Tactical, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_a3">	
		<text>Steyr AUG A3</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_aug_a3_descr">	
		<text>Steyr AUG (Armee Universal Gewehr - Army Universal Rifle) is an Austrian 5.56x45mm NATO bullpup assault rifle, designed in the 1960s by Steyr-Daimler-Puch and now manufactured by Steyr Mannlicher GmbH & Co KG. The Steyr AUG A3 differs from the base model in the presence of four Picatinny slats: the top one is used for attaching sights, a grenade launcher or a vertical front handle can be attached to the bottom, and a laser pointer or other necessary additional equipment is attached to the side.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, C-more Railway Tactical, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mk14">	
		<text>Mk 14 EBR</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mk14_descr">	
		<text>United States Navy Mark 14 Enhanced Battle Rifle (Mk 14 Enhanced Battle Rifle, "improved combat rifle") - American Marksman rifle, created by special operations of the US Navy based on the M14 rifle. Used by a number of special units of the Navy, including SEAL.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, C-more Railway Tactical, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_fal">	
		<text>FN FAL</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fal_descr">	
		<text>FN FAL is a NATO firearm produced in Belgium by Fabrique Nationale de Herstal. One of the most recognized and popular automatic rifles. The FN FAL was originally developed for an intermediate 7.92x33 mm cartridge used by the Germans during World War II, then prototypes for the .280 British cartridge appeared. It was later remade chambered for 7.62x51 mm NATO, adopted as a single patron for NATO countries. During the Cold War, it received the nickname "the right hand of the free world."\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, C-more Railway Tactical, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_fort500">	
		<text>Fort-500</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fort500_descr">	
		<text>The Fort-500 smoothbore rifle was developed by the Fort NGO of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of Ukraine in the late 1990s, and was intended to arm the staff of the Ministry of Internal Affairs and security services of Ukraine. At present, the FORT-500 rifle in limited quantities is in service with the special units of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of Ukraine, and is also sold to citizens of this country in a hunting variant.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m82">	
		<text>Barrett M82</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m82_descr">	
		<text>Barrett M82, in the documentation of the US Armed Forces M107 - American self-loading large-caliber sniper rifle, manufactured by Barrett Firearms Manufacturing and in service with several countries around the world. The automatics of this rifle are based on a butterfly valve. The rifle belongs to the class of "antimaterial", but is more often used as a weapon against enemy infantry.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_remington700">	
		<text>Remington 700</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_remington700_descr">	
		<text>There are many options for a different rifle cartridge. Standard cartridge - 7.62x51 mm NATO (.308 Win). Technically, it is a magazine rifle with a longitudinally sliding rotary bolt. Store capacity depends on the caliber and can be from 3 to 5. It is a top product from Remington Arms.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] KZRZP suppressor (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_remington870">	
		<text>Remington 870</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_remington870_descr">	
		<text>Remington 870 is an American gun, first introduced in 1950 by Remington Arms. Due to its characteristic recharge is one of the most famous pump-action rifles in the world. Produced in various versions, it is suitable for both the military and the police, for hunters and athletes, as well as for self-defense.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Barska ES AC10632, C-more Railway Tactical, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_wa2000">	
		<text>Walther WA 2000</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_wa2000_descr">	
		<text>The Walther WA 2000 is a semi-automatic bullpup sniper rifle produced by the Carl Walther GmbH Sportwaffen company from 1982 until 1988. It was produced in three different calibers. Production of the rifle was limited and it was shortly stopped because it was too expensive to achieve widespread sales and not robust enough for military use as a sniper rifle. Only 176 were built due to its high cost, making it one of the rarest and most sought production firearms ever made.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] KZRZP suppressor (wymaga modyfikacji)\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_apb">	
		<text>Wyt³umiony APB</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_apb_descr">	
		<text>The APB (Avtomaticheskij Pistolet Besshumnyj – automatic silenced pistol) is a further development of the Stechkin APS automatic pistol. APB has been developed by 1972 for Soviet Spetsnaz and KGB units, and has been widely used in Afghanistan and later conflicts. All APB pistols were reworked from earlier Stechkin APS pistols. The APB, with the silencer fitted, is as loud as a non-silenced .22 caliber pistol, and is very accurate and controllable, especially with the shoulder stock fitted.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_cz52">	
		<text>CZ 52</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_cz52_descr">	
		<text>The CZ 52 (also known by the Czechoslovak military designations vz. 52, for (vz. - vzor = model) "model of 1952", and CZ 482) is a semi-automatic pistol designed by two brothers, Jan and Jaroslav Kratochvil, in the early 1950s for the Czechoslovak military. Around 200,000 vz. 52s were made by Ceska Zbrojovka in Strakonice from 1952 to 1954. Before standardizing on the 7.62x25mm vz. 52, the Czechoslovak military used several domestic and foreign pistol models in three different calibers.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_fnc">	
		<text>FN FNC</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_fnc_descr">	
		<text>The FNC (Fabrique Nationale Carabine) is a 5.56x45mm NATO assault rifle developed by the Belgian arms manufacturer FN Herstal and introduced in the late 1970s.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n \n
		</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_hk417">	
		<text>HK417</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_hk417_descr">	
		<text>The Heckler & Koch HK417 is a battle rifle designed and manufactured by Heckler & Koch in Germany. It is the larger caliber version of the HK416, and chambered for the full-power 7.62x51mm NATO rifle cartridge. It is a gas-operated, selective fire rifle with a rotating bolt. The HK417 is intended for use in roles where the greater penetrative power, stopping power, and range of the 7.62x51mm cartridge are required. It has been adopted for service by a number of armed forces, special forces, and police organizations.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_m60">	
		<text>M60</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_m60_descr">	
		<text>The M60, officially the United States Machine Gun, Caliber 7.62 mm, M60, is a family of American general-purpose machine guns firing 7.62x51mm NATO cartridges from a disintegrating belt of M13 links. There are several types of amunicja approved for use in the M60, including ball, tracer, and armor-piercing rounds.\n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_mp7">	
		<text>MP7</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_mp7_descr">	
		<text>The Heckler & Koch MP7 (Maschinenpistole 7) is a German personal defence weapon (PDW) designed and manufactured by Heckler & Koch (H&K) and chambered for the HK 4.6x30mm cartridge. It was designed with the new cartridge to meet NATO requirements published in 1989, as these requirements call for a personal defense weapon (PDW) class firearm, with a greater ability to penetrate body armor than current weapons limited to conventional pistol cartridges. The MP7 went into production in 2001.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 9x19 compatible \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, C-more Railway Tactical, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_xm8">	
		<text>XM8</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_xm8_descr">	
		<text>The XM8 is a lightweight assault rifle system from the late 1990s to early 2000s. The rifle was designed by German small arms manufacturer Heckler & Koch (H&K), and shares design and engineering with their G36 rifle.\n
		The XM8 design was originally part of the Objective Individual Combat Weapon program (OICW), which was developing a "smart" grenade launcher system with an underslung carbine rifle. The system was unable to meet performance and weight requirements and was eventually cancelled. In the aftermath, the two portions of the OICW were separated, resulting in the XM8 and XM25 projects.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_2]OSPRZÊT: \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] t³umik kompatybilny z kalibrem 5.56x45\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, C-more Railway Tactical, EOTech \n \n</text>
	</string>	
		
		
<!--		
Grenades		
-->		
	<string id="st_grenade_f1">	
		<text>Granat F1</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_grenade_f1_descr">	
		<text>A defensive hand grenade, with fragments capable of piercing medium level body armour. The grenade has an approximately 4 metre kill radius. Stalkers get F1 grenades from trading with the military, who write them off as having been used for fighting mutants.\n \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast power: %c[ui_gray_1]high\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast radius: %c[ui_gray_1]4.2 m\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fragments' radius: %c[ui_gray_1]48 m\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Av. number of fragments: %c[ui_gray_1]380 (small shrapnels)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Explosion delay: %c[ui_gray_1]~4 seconds</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_grenade_rgd5">	
		<text>Granat RGD-5</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_grenade_rgd5_descr">	
		<text>An offensive hand grenade with a small kill zone of about 3 metres. Often used by stalkers to "smoke out" mutants due to its relatively low cost.\n \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast power: %c[ui_gray_1]medium\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast radius: %c[ui_gray_1]3,2 m\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fragments' radius: %c[ui_gray_1]43 m\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Av. number of fragments: %c[ui_gray_1]240 (small shrapnels)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Explosion delay: %c[ui_gray_1]~4 seconds</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_grenade_smoke">	
		<text>Granat dymny</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_grenade_smoke_descr">	
		<text>A hand smoke grenade. Used to put up smoke screens. Once the grenade is thrown it takes 10 seconds for the smoke screen to expand.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_grenade_thermite">	
		<text>Granat termitowy</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_grenade_thermite_descr">	
		<text>An incendiary grenade (or thermite grenade) that produces intense heat (2,200 °C or 3,992 °F) by means of a chemical reaction in which powdered aluminium and iron oxide react to produce a stream of molten iron and aluminium oxide. Filled with 600 to 800 grams of thermite.\n \n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast power: %c[ui_gray_1]medium (thermal damage)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast radius: %c[ui_gray_1]4.6 m\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fragments' radius: %c[ui_gray_1]none\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Av. number of fragments: %c[ui_gray_1]none\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Explosion delay: %c[ui_gray_1]~4 seconds</text>
	</string>	
		
<!--		
	Melee	
-->		
	<string id="st_knife_combat">	
		<text>Bagnet M9</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_knife_combat_descr">	
		<text>\n \n%c[ui_gray_1]A large multi-purpose knife with a rugged rubber handle, commonly used by US soldiers since 1986. Sharp and well maintained. Although it's inconvenienced when facing heavily protected opponents, its toothed blade is ideal for causing massive, bleeding wounds to softer targets. This is makes it a perfect choice for finishing off wounded animals, or silently getting the drop on light infantry.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_knife_6x4">	
		<text>Bagnet 6H4</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_knife_6x4_descr">	
		<text>\n \n%c[ui_gray_1]Soviet-Polish bayonet first adopted in 1972 for use with AK rifles. Although highly durable, it is much better at thrusting than it is at chopping or slashing.\n \n
		%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] unsuitable for chopping thick-skinned mutants</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_knife_hunting">	
		<text>Nó¿ myœliwski</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_knife_hunting_descr">	
		<text>\n \n%c[ui_gray_1]A modern, highly durable hunting knife with a large blade of stainless steel. Ideal for field dressing the meat off larger animals with thick hides. It is also able to cause massive, bleeding wounds to exposed flesh. As it wasn't intended for use in battle, it struggles against combat armours.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_knife_m">	
		<text>Nó¿ wojskowy</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_knife_m_descr">	
		<text>\n \n%c[ui_gray_1]NOT IN GAME. Standard issue military knife.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_knife_needle">	
		<text>Nó¿ harcerski NR-40</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_knife_needle_descr">	
		<text>\n \n%c[ui_gray_1]A combat knife, based on designs first adopted by the Soviet Army in WWII. It is technically surplus, and isn't officially used by any modern army.\n \nThis weapon consists of a 152 mm blade with a clip point, a large choil, a black wooden handle, and an S-shaped guard. The guard is "inverted" because standard Soviet Army grips frequently called for holding the knife with the edge facing upwards. The handle is enforced with rugged fabric for a good grip.\n \nAlthough a good combat knife for its time, in the Zone its cutting power is suitable only for utility purposes or for finishing off already helpless opponents. Its piercing power, however, is something to be feared: it is easy to angle this blade's deadly point between the gaps of even modern combat armours.\n \n
		%c[d_red] • %c[d_red] unsuitable for chopping thick-skinned mutants.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_knife_nr40">	
		<text>Nó¿ harcerski NR-40 (pami¹tka)</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_knife_nr40_descr">	
		<text>\n \n%c[ui_gray_1]NOT IN GAME. A rare Soviet military knife of high historic and symbolic value. Decorated with the iron emblem of a certain World War II parachute division on the wooden handle. Possession of such a blade is usually a mark of honour, especially among factions with a proud military tradition. Usually offered to stalkers only after exceptional displays of loyal, competent service to a given faction or group of traders.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_knife_swat">	
		<text>Nó¿ Specnazu</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_knife_swat_descr">	
		<text>A well-kept blade, ideal for special forces operators participating in surgical strikes. Rumoured to have averted several nuclear incidents during the Cold War. It is a deadly weapon and the only knife in the Zone that is relatively good at both piercing armours and dealing massive tissue damage. The ultimate combat cutlery.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_axe">	
		<text>Siekiera</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_axe_descr">	
		<text>An axe (or ax) is an implement that has been used for millennia to shape, split and cut wood, to harvest timber, as a weapon, and as a ceremonial or heraldic symbol. The axe has many forms but generally consists of an axe head with a handle, or helve. In the Zone, the axe can ensure your survival thanks to its versatility.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_1]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] melee weapon\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] has greater reach compared to knives\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_axe2">	
		<text>Siekiera stra¿acka</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_axe2_descr">	
		<text>Most commonly employed by firefighters, this heavy axe is often used by stalkers for felling trees, or, like all great things, repurposed for hacking apart one's enemies, living or dead. Thus, it can serve as a formidable weapon in the hands of a skilled stalker.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_1]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] melee weapon\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] has greater reach compared to knives\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_axe3">	
		<text>Siekiera myœliwska</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_axe3_descr">	
		<text>Used for thousands of years for cutting wood, hacking flesh, and even as a ceremonial object, this convenient axe comes in many shapes, though always consisting of a cleaver and handle. In a place like the Zone, this axe can mean both life and death.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_1]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] melee weapon\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] has greater reach compared to knives\n
		%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_grenade_light">	
		<text>Granat M68</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_grenade_light_descr">	
		<text>The M68 lightweight grenade packs a considerable amount of shrapnel and is popular among paratroopers, marines and special NATO forces. Fitted with the M213 fuse, it can be worn and rapidly deployed by hooking the trigger lever to the equipment belt.</text>
	</string>	
		
	<string id="st_wpn_flamewerfer">	
		<text>Miotacz ognia</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_wpn_flamewerfer_descr">	
		<text>A home-made flamethrower, prone to jamming and having poor range. Its haphazard design suggests it was made in the zone by a disturbed stalker.</text>
	</string>	
</string_table>